奋斗的乔伊/翻转幸福(台)/欢姐当自强(港)
Joy
美国　剧情/喜剧/传记 2015
奥斯卡金像奖(2016；第88届) 提名
奥斯卡奖-最佳女主角詹妮弗·劳伦斯 Jennifer Lawrence
美国金球奖(2016；第73届)
获奖
电影类-音乐喜剧类最佳女主角詹妮弗·劳伦斯 Jennifer Lawrence
提名
电影类-音乐喜剧类最佳影片
这说不通
It doesn't make sense
我不明白怎么会发生这样的事
I don't understand how something like this happened
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what I'm gonna do
那曾是我全部的人生 现在却消失了
This has been my whole life, and now it's gone
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what I'm supposed to do
我只熟知彭德尔顿产业
Pendleton Industries is all I've ever known
现在全都被夺走了
And now it's all been taken away
当别人看见了我的弱点 我会把那个弱点化为力量
When someone sees a weakness in me, I turn that weakness into a strength
丹妮卡，你真坚强
Danica, you're so strong
我做不出这样的事
I don't think I could do anything like this
克拉琳达，你可以去争取那块地
You can imagine changing your life...
来改变你的生活
by fighting for the deed to the land, Clarinda
只要巴塞洛缪离世
Which is only possible if Bartholomew is no longer living
你永远也不会再得到那块地
You will never get the deed to the land again
我永远也不会准许
I will never allow it
把枪放下，你这个傻瓜
Put down that gun, you silly girl
小心点，巴塞洛缪
Watch your step, Bartholomew
里奇正赶来
Ridge is on his way
他仍爱着克拉琳达
And he's still in love with Clarinda
贾里德爱着我
And Jared loves me
克拉琳达
Clarinda...
没错
it's true
我为你而来
I'm here for you
根据一名勇敢女子的真实故事改编
一名特别的女子
这是乔伊的故事 由我，她的外婆来讲讲
This is the story of Joy, as told by me, her grandmother
每个人都从梦想中的生活开始
Everybody starts out with some kind of dream of what life will be
鲁迪公车和货车公司
乔伊的梦想从她爸爸经营的 这家修车厂开始
Joy's dream started at this metal garage her father ran
杰基，杰基，往后走 有香蕉和弗兰基
Jackie, Jackie, bo-backie Banana-fana, fo-fackie
菲飞，麦基儿 杰基
Fee-fi, mo-mackie Jackie
我的孙女有个好朋友叫杰基
My granddaughter had a best friend, Jackie
乔伊，乔伊，男孩子们 有香蕉和礼物
Joy, Joy, bo-boy Banana-fana, fo-foy
我的脚在颤抖
While shivering in my shoes
我才不在乎
I strike a careless pose
还有一个同夫异母的姐姐，佩吉
A half-sister, Peggy
一条狗
A dog
没事的，米茨
It's okay It's okay, Mitzy
父亲
A father
母亲
A mother...
也就是我女儿
who is my daughter
外婆，就是我
A grandmother That's me
她在房间里做了好多漂亮的东西
She made many beautiful things in her room
真是神奇
Magic
有些人很喜欢造东西
Some people love to make things
他们有耐心，能集中精神 用双手解决问题
They have the patience and the focus to figure it out with their hands
乔伊就是那样喜欢造东西的人
Joy was one of those people who rejoiced in making things
我打开通向大片草地的大门
And I open the gate to the big g reen meadow
我走进森林
And I went into the forest
在那我克服了很多危险
And there, I conquered many dangers
一头狼
A wolf...
和其他吓人的东西
and other scary things
然后我开始造我自己的房子
And then I started to build my very own house...
我会住在那里
where I would live...
然后创造很多美好的东西 让全世界
and make wonderful creations for all the world...
都看到和拥有
to see and have
或者给住在森林那边
And maybe for the prince and princess...
城堡里的王子和公主
who lived across the forest, in the castle
看见吗？
See?
他们相爱着
And they were in love
因为我造的东西
And maybe they'd invite me over...
他们可能会邀请我去做客
because of the things that I made
你需要一个帅气的王子 那是你需要的，一个王子
You need a handsome prince That's what you need A prince
不，我不需要王子
No, I don't need a prince
这是超能力，我不需要王子
This is a special power I don't need a prince
我的女儿泰瑞与丈夫分居 独自待在房间里
My daughter Terry is separated, and alone in her room...
看肥皂剧
watching soap operas
克拉琳达，你可以去争取那块地
You can imagine changing your life...
来改变你的生活
by fighting for the deed to the land, Clarinda
我有样东西给你
I have something for you
哦，丹妮卡
Oh, Danica...
你真坚强
You're so strong
我做不出这样的事
I don't think I could ever do something like this
我一直觉得我该鼓励她
I always felt it was for me to encourage her
所以我说
So I said...
你会长成一名坚强、睿智的聪明女子
You are goi ng to g row up and be a strong, smart young woman...
去上学，遇到一个好男人 有自己漂亮的孩子们
go to school, meet a fine young man, have beautiful children of your own...
创造出像你房间里那些 美好的东西来
and you're gonna build wonderful things that you do in your room
好吗？
Okay?
这个女孩的梦想如何了？
What happened to this girl's dreams?
看看吧
Watch this
妈妈，我找不到工牌的挂绳了
Mother, I can't find my lanyard for work
没有它他们不会让我通过机场的安检
They're not gonna let me through airport security without it
乔伊，找不到你的挂绳了？ 我能帮你吗？
Joy, you can't find your lanyard? Can I help you?
不用，我…
No, but I...
亲爱的，听着
Honey, listen
我知道生活并不像 我们多次谈过的那样，亲爱的
I know life hasn't gone as we discussed many times, sweetheart
而你的人生也不是刚刚开始
And you don't exactly have your whole life ahead of you...
但仍有很长的一段路
but you still have a good portion of it, anyway
面包总会有的
Hope springs eternal
–谢了，外婆 –不谢
- Thanks, Mimi - Sure
妈妈，看我找到了什么
Mother, look what I did find
那是什么？
What is that?
你怎么能不知道？
How can you ask what this is?
我高中时发明的狗项圈
The dog collar I invented in high school
记不记得米茨被卡住几次？
Remember Mitzy choked a couple of times?
所以我发明了一个可快速解开的狗项圈
So I invented a dog collar with a quick release...
这样狗永远也不会被卡住
so that a dog would never choke...
我还在上面贴了反光贴 而且它还是个防跳蚤项圈
and I covered it with reflective tape, plus it's a flea collar
如果你帮我申请了专利或请个律师
I probably wouldn't be late to this job I'm going to...
可能我就不用帮人打工了
if you'd gotten me a patent or a lawyer
实干家乔伊 你总是在造各种东西，亲爱的
Joy the doer, Joy the doer You were always doing things, honey
我怎能每一样都记住呢？
How could I be expected to remember everything?
现在哈茨公司拥有了这个专利权
Now the Hartz company has the patent to that collar
我不知道怎么申请专利
I don't know how to get a patent
那是什么味道？
What is that smell?
这下面怎么会有酸奶，妈妈？
How did you get yogurt down here, Mother?
我也在想那是什么味道呢
I was wondering what that odor was
已经开始发霉了
It's starting to mold for Pete's sake
是的，因为我不能让生活就这样弃我而去
Yes, I am, because I feel like I cannot have the life bled out of me this way
乔伊，看谁回来了，看谁回来了！
Joy, look who's back Look who's back!
没错，巴塞洛缪回来了
Yes, Bartholomew is back
不，不
No, no
我以为巴塞洛缪已经死了
I thought Bartholomew was dead?
我是个鬼魂
And I'm a ghost
他化作力量更强的鬼魂回来了
He came back as a ghost with even greater powers
鬼魂，走开！
Ghost, you go away!
我现在力量更强了
My powers are even greater now
我做不到，这怎么可能？
I cannot handle this How is this possible?
别靠近他
Stay away from him
克拉琳达，即使在坟墓里
Clarinda, you don't know what a ghost can do to you!
你也不知道鬼魂能把你怎么样！
Even from beyond the grave
外婆会带你去参加生日会，好吧？
Grandma's gonna take you to the birthday party, okay?
只要五分钟
Five minutes
嗨，你们来这干什么？
Hi What are you doing here?
我来把他还给你，我不想要了
I'm returning him to you I don't want him anymore
什么？
What?
他精神不正常
He's damaged
他无处可去
He has no place else to go
他在我的房子里住了两年了
He's been living in my house for two years
爸爸，我真抱歉
Dad, I'm so sorry
但你知道，托尼住在地下室
But you know, Tony's living in the basement
你前夫不该住在你的地下室
Your ex-husband shouldn't be living in your basement
离婚了还这样不合适
That's not the proper way to be divorced
好吧，我不知道该让你住哪里
Okay I don't know where I'm gonna put you
爸爸，别进去，妈妈在里面
Dad, don't go in there Mom's in there
你可以跟他在一起了，泰瑞 我不想了
You can have him back, Terry I don't want him anymore
跟莎伦在一起有什么好的，鲁迪？
What was so much better about being with Sharon, Rudy?
爸爸，别回答
Dad, don't answer that
我们能一起去大都会艺术博物馆
We went to the Metropolitan Museum of Art
–你喜欢博物馆什么？ –我喜欢什么？我来告诉你
- What did you like at the museum? - What did I like? I'll tell you what I like
我喜欢古老的罗马雕像、中世纪的盔甲
I like the ancient Roman statues I like the medieval armor
伊特鲁里亚人的珠宝
I like the Etruscan jewelry
–博物馆里全是灰尘和死物 –我喜欢去那个咖啡馆
- Museums are full of dust and death - I like going to the café...
喝杯浓咖啡，吃个好吃的意式热三明治
having an espresso, a nice panini, that's what I like
你在棺材里吃意式热三明治，鲁迪
You had a panini in a coffin, Rudy
–一个布满灰尘、无趣的棺材，恶心 –那你还问？
- A dusty, boring coffin Yuck - Then why'd you ask me?
你是个疯子吗？
What are you, a crazy person?
我就像是在跟一个疯子讲话
It's like having a conversation with an insane asylum person
还有什么，杰克船长？ 还有什么好看的？
What else, Captain Jack? What else was so great?
你叫我杰克船长，好吧
Captain Jack, you're calling me Okay
对，杰克船长，一个大坏蛋
Yes, you're Captain Jack, the flying jackass
是的，你知道你是谁吗？ 你就像是泄漏的煤气
Yeah, and you know what you are? You're like a gas leak
–闻不到、看不到… –我不是泄漏的煤气
- We don't smell you, we don't see you... - I am not a gas leak!
–但能慢慢地把我们都杀了 –你把那话收回
- But you're killing us all silently - You take that back...
告诉我你还跟莎伦做过什么！
and tell me what else you did with Sharon!
你就是个妖怪
You creature from the Black Lagoon
住嘴！你们俩都别说了
No! This conversation is over
–我要走了，祝你好运 –天，又这样
- I'm leaving Good luck - Oh, my God Here it goes
小心，乔伊，他要发飙了！
Watch out, Joy He's gonna snap!
你想让我发飙，你的惯用伎俩，你…
Please You want me to snap That's your whole routine You...
保护瓷器！
Guard the china!
–嘿，泰瑞，你喜欢这个吗？ –爸爸，不要！
- Hey, Terry, you like this? - Dad, no!
这样发飙如何？
How's this for snapping?
–不要！ –这样如何？
- No! No - How's this?
这就是发飙！
This is snapping!
–爸爸！住手！ –他心理失常，乔伊！
- Dad! Stop! - He's disturbed, Joy!
他是个心理失常的人！
He's a disturbed man!
–我心理失常？ –他是个神经病！
- I'm disturbed? - He's a damaged man!
你说的对，我心理失常
You're right, I am disturbed
是你让我心理失常的
You're the great disturber!
对不起，亲爱的
I'm sorry, honey
我不希望这样的
I don't like this
你不该看见这样的事
You're not supposed to see this kind of thing
我非常非常抱歉，我诚意道歉
I'm very, very sorry I apologize sincerely
不会发生的，好吧？我们有另一个…
It's not gonna happen, okay? We have other...
我来收拾干净
I'm gonna clean all this up
爸爸，不用收拾了
Dad, no Don't clean it up
爸爸，住手，别收拾好吧？
Dad, stop Just don't, okay?
住手，我来收拾 你离开这间房间吧
Stop I'll do it I just want to get you out of this room
谢谢你
Thank you
嗨，伙计们，真对不起
Hi, guys I'm sorry about all the yelling
太婆会带你们去生日会，好吧？
Mimi's gonna take you to the birthday party, okay?
嗨，宝贝们
Hi, my sweethearts
–你又打烂东西了 –他是把东西打烂了
- You broke things again - He did break stuff
我是把东西打烂了，但外婆有错
I did break some things, but Grandma was wrong
我做错了一点事，但她是大错
So I was a little wrong, but she was really wrong
外公会跟我们一起住一段时间
But Grandpa's gonna come stay with us for a little while
太好了！
Yay!
跟外公一起过夜！太好了！
A sleepover with Grandpa! Yay!
莎伦永远不分开洗衣服 白色总是被染成灰色
Sharon never separated the wash The whites were always gray
但你很会洗这个，宝贝 我能托你洗一下吗？
But you have that magic touch, sweetheart, so could I give this to you, please?
好，我来洗，去拿包吧
Yeah, I'll take care of it, yeah Just get your bag
我那些账本怎么办？我的会计账本？
What about my ledgers and all that stuff? My accounting books?
我来处理，今天我会拿给你
I got them I'll get them to you later today
–我爱你，外公 –我爱你
- I love you, Grandpa - Love you
–我帮你报了税，还有税表 –好，那很重要
- I did your taxes, I did your W-2s - Okay Very important
你唱得很难听！
You suck!
他在这做什么？
What is he doing here?
莎伦把他带回来了
Sharon brought him back...
在他找到新的爱人或者住的地方之前 他会跟我们住
so he's gonna stay with us until he finds a new love or a new place to live
你知道是怎么回事
You know how this goes
爸爸，起来
Dad, up
你们俩离了婚就不该如此
This is not the proper way to be divorced, the two of you
你要来告诉我离了婚该怎么样吗？
You're gonna tell me how to be divorced?
我有所贡献，大歌星 我有自己的生意
I'm a provider, Tom Jones I have my own business
我帮乔伊付了房贷，你呢？
I help Joy with the mortgage What do you do?
你整晚在安吉拉斯塔波莉的俱乐部唱歌
You sing all night at Angela Starpoli's club
你数次被金宝汤公司解雇
You get repeatedly fired from Campbell's Soup
好，我会把地下室分隔一下
Okay, well I'm gonna divide the basement
我已离婚，我想干什么都行，鲁迪
I'm divorced I can do whatever I want, Rudy
离婚了还这样不合适
This is not the proper way to be divorced
我上班就快迟到了
And I'm about to be late for work
请你们不要在孩子面前吵架，好吗？
So please try not to fight in front of the children, okay?
尤其不要动手
Especially not physically
鲁迪，你看见这个了吗？ 这个麦克风
Rudy, you see this? This microphone here?
你碰它我就杀了你
You touch it, and I kill you
好，我要走了
Okay I'm leaving
我不在的时候请你们别要对方的命
Please try not to kill each other while I'm gone
你疯了，这都是你的错！
You've gone mad This is all your fault!
克拉琳达，克拉琳达！别这样
Clarinda Clarinda! Don't
克拉琳达，发生了很糟糕的事！ 离他远点！
Clarinda, something terrible happened! Stay away from him!
哦，我的天，我以为修好了呢
Oh, my God I thought I fixed this thing
干得好，干得真好
N ice job, Joy N ice job
佩吉？你在这干什么？
Peggy? What are you doing here?
你怎么搞的？外婆有关节炎
What's the matter with you? Sending Grandma Mimi with her arthritis...
你还让她带他们去参加生日会？
to take them to their friend's birthday?
我没事
I'm fine
他们跟我，还有佩吉阿姨在一起会更开心
They have a much better time with me anyway, with Aunt Peggy
我可不会愚蠢到步入一段糟糕的婚姻 生几个孩子
But I wasn't stupid enough to get into a bad marriage and have a couple of kids
别烦你妹妹，佩吉
Don't bother your sister, Peggy
我去跟爸爸谈点生意，好吧？
I'm gonna talk to Dad about business All right?
你晚点会把账本带回车库吗？
You gonna come bring the books by the garage later?
是的，我晚点带回来，他在地下室
Yeah, I'm gonna bring them later He's in the basement
我刚才是在开玩笑
I'm joking with you
对，我知道
Yeah I know
孩子们，我们晚点去玩，好吧？
Kids, we're gonna do something fun later, okay?
我们现在就在玩
We're doing something fun now
哦，我们在克利夫兰找到了你的行李
Oh, we found your luggage but it's in Cleveland
所以现在只需把它运回纽约
So now we just need to get it back to New York City
我要正式投诉
I'm filing a complaint
我丈夫需要他的药
My husband needs his medication
你叫什么名字？乔伊？
What's your name? Joy?
今天我看你不太高兴啊
You don't seem joyous to me today
可能我今天就是不太高兴
Perhaps I am not so joyous today
–乔伊，你要被降职了 –嗨，你还好吗？
- Joy, I think you're getting demoted - Hi, how you doing?
你要跟总监谈一下
Listen, I need you to speak to the supervisor
我们会做一些变动，你要上晚班
We're gonna be having some changes, and you're gonna be going to the night hours
–晚班？汤姆，我不能上晚班 –我们要削减开支
- Night hours? Tom, I can't work night hours - And we're having cutbacks
–我有两个孩子 –乔伊，对不起
- I've got two kids - Joy, I'm sorry
祝你好运
Good luck
再见，苏姗
Bye, Susan
我没收到货不会付钱的
I'm not paying for metal that I haven't gotten
另外我发了…他想要钱
On top of me send... You know, he wants to get paid
他没发发票来，连货也没发来
He doesn't send an invoice, and he hasn't even sent the metal
当地生意人重振公司雄风
他为何不把发票发过来？ 把发票发过来，我就会付他钱
But why doesn't he just send the invoice? Send the invoice, I'll pay him
对，就这样，把发票发过来
Yep That's it Send the invoice
嗨，爸爸，我想再次谢谢你帮忙付房贷
Hi Dad, I want to thank you again for helping with the mortgage
好
Yeah
我对了帐，做了账本
I settled the accounts, balanced the books
谢谢你
Thank you
我很抱歉生意那么差，爸爸
I'm sorry business is so bad, Dad
旁边的练枪场影响很大
I don't think that that crazy gun range is helping
那怎么还能合法？
How is that still legal?
–我能怎么办？ –都这么多年了
- What can I do? - After all these years?
他们在自己的地盘练
They keep to themselves
那是他们的地方，警察也管不了
It's their property The police leave them alone
怎么？你觉得生意受它影响？
Why? You think it's costing us business?
我觉得一定没好处
I don't think it's helping
如果你想帮忙 为何你不来这管理这个地方？
Well, if you wanna help, why don't you come here and manage this place?
我也想更上一层楼，穿上漂亮的套装
You know, I'd like to go the next level Put on a nice suit
出去找客户
You know, go out there and get some accounts
对，我是9873，想查查我的信箱
Yeah, this is 9873 Just checking my mailbox
那是什么？
What is that?
我有笔，请说
Yeah, I have a pen What is it?
13–14，就这样？
13-14 That's it?
谢谢你
Thank you
那是什么？
What was that?
那是付费电话
It's a 900 number
什么付费电话？
What's a 900 number?
一个提供给寡妇和鳏夫的约会服务
It's, you know, a dating service for widows and widowers
约会服务？
Dating service?
你不是鳏夫啊？
You're not a widow or a widower
有什么区别？我是单身
What's the difference? I'm single
我能遇见好的女人，可能我们会爱上对方
I meet nice ladies Maybe we fall in love
我要坠入爱河，否则不感兴趣 你知道的
I have to fall in love or I'm not interested You know me
我知道，爸爸
I know, Dad
莎伦跟他不合适，认识新的人对他有好处
Sharon was no good for him It's nice for him to meet somebody new
–我给他买了些新衣服 –好吧
- I got him some new clothes, you know? - Okay Okay
–你好？你是7633吗？ –很好，高兴点吧
- Hello? Is this 7633? - It's good, THEN JOY TO PEGGY
–好，我爱你，迟点见 –是的
- Okay I love you See you later - Yes?
再见
Bye
嗨，我是9833
Hi This is 9833
嗨！你好吗？
Hi! Hi, how are you?
你的声音很好听
What a nice voice you have
谢谢你
Thank you
–哦，你有口音 –是的
- Oh, an accent - Yes
我来自意大利
I am from Italy
哦！欧洲
Oh! Continental
你叫什么名字？
What is your name?
我叫鲁迪，你呢？
My name is Rudy, what's yours?
特鲁迪
Trudy
–开玩笑吧？ –不是
- Are you kidding me? - No
你叫特鲁迪？
Your name is Trudy?
是的！
Yes!
鲁迪和特鲁迪，我很喜欢
Rudy and Trudy I love it
我们商量一下什么时候见面吧
Let's figure out when we're gonna meet
好主意，我们一起吃晚饭吧
That's a good idea Let's have dinner
–我可以来接你 –好
- I could come pick you up - Yeah
我开一辆绿色的奔驰车
I have a green Mercedes
好，6点半？我会准备好的
Okay, 6:30? I'll be ready
再见
Ciao
祝你约会顺利，爸爸
Good luck with your date, Dad
谢谢，我很兴奋
Thank you I'm excited
你要穿什么去？
What do you think you're gonna wear?
拉夫劳伦马球牌衣服
Polo by Ralph Lauren
你非要喷整瓶古龙水吗？
Did you have to use the whole bottle of cologne?
托尼！
Tony!
你闻起来像我外婆 他闻起来像我外婆
You smell like my grandmother He smells like my grandmother
嘿，拜托，别让我紧张
Hey, please Don't make me tense
别把我搞得那么紧张 我要保持放松的心情
Don't stress me out I gotta stay nice and loose
–现在你紧张了？ –我紧张了，你搞得我紧张了
- Now you're tense? - I'm tense You're making me tense
–伙计们，求你们别吵了 –我让你紧张了？
- Guys, stop Please - I'm making you tense?
我的车在等着了
My carriage awaits
约会愉快
Have a great date
祝我好运
Wish me luck
你不需要运气
You don't need it
乔伊，拿水来！
Joy, water!
我的袖扣呢？
Where are my cufflinks?
妈咪，来给我讲故事！
Mommy, come read to me!
等五分钟，克里斯蒂
Five minutes, Cristy
妈妈，又这样？
Mother, again?
对，你就坐那吧，舒服吗？
Yeah, you just sit right there Are you comfortable?
我跟你说了多少次 不要在水池里洗梳子！
How many times do I have to tell you not to clean your brushes out in the sink!
丹妮卡觉得把东西扔进马桶不是淑女作风
Danica thinks it's unladylike to toss things in the toilet
我也认同
And I happen to agree
是吗？那让丹妮卡来修水管吧
Yeah? Well, why don't you have Danica do your plumbing then?
丹妮卡能选择在任何地方施展才华
Danica can direct her power anywhere Danica chooses
那就是丹妮卡的能力
That is the power of Danica
哦，我的天
Oh, my God
如果这个问题继续恶化
If this problem gets any worse...
我们就要让你搬去另一间房间
we're gonna have to move you into a different room
也就是说不会再有电视
That means no TV
对你来讲很可怕吧
That could be very scary for you
别那么做，乔伊，这是我舒适的窝
Don't let that happen, Joy This is my comfort nest
我们要请水管工来看看
We're gonna need to get a plumber in here
什么？
What?
会有个男人来我的房间？
There's gonna... A man in my room?
除了我，我不认识其他女水管工了
Well, I don't know any female plumbers other than me
你修不了吗，乔伊？
Well, can't you fix it, Joy?
那超出我的能力范围了
This has surpassed my capabilities
谢了，乔伊
Thanks, Joy
“蝉是一种大型飞行类昆虫 五到八厘米长
"The cicada is a large flying insect two to three inches long
“它能发出高达120分贝的声音 比一些电话铃声还响
"It makes a sound of up to 120 decibels, louder than some telephones
“它生命中的一半时间 都在躲避天敌
"It lives half of its life above ground evading predators
你想让我给你念这本书吗，克里斯蒂？
This is the book you wanted me to read to you, Cristy?
我们的房子里怎么会有这本书？
How did this book even get in the house?
佩吉阿姨给我的
Aunt Peggy got it for me
她说我之所以像蝉 是因为它们让空气中充斥着声音
She said the reason I like cicadas is because they fill the air with sound...
好让这个房子没那么孤单
which makes the house less lonelier for me
佩吉阿姨告诉你房子觉得孤单时 你是什么感觉？
Aunt Peggy tells you how you feel about the house being lonely?
佩吉阿姨告诉了我很多事
Aunt Peggy tells me a lot of things
请继续念
Keep reading, please
我不想你听太多佩吉阿姨的话
I don't want you listening to Aunt Peggy too much
好，为什么？
Okay Why?
“蝉在很多国家都代表了重生
"The cicada, a symbol of rebirth in many countries...
“钻进地下生活可长达17年之久”
"digs into the ground and stays buried for up to 17 years"
这么奇怪的数字，为何是17年？
That's such a random number Why 17 years?
都没解释为何
It doesn't even say why
我知道一年有四季
I understand the four seasons in a year...
但为何有东西要隐藏17年？
but why would something stay hidden for 17 years?
那太没道理了，我不念了
That's just unsettling I'm not reading this
你也困了，我们去睡吧
You're sleepy anyway We gotta go to bed
我想跟外婆睡
I wanna sleep with Nana
不行，你要在自己房间睡
No, you should sleep upstairs in your room
我要外婆
I want Nana
好，小心，这里有个洞
All right Well, watch out There's a hole here
我就躺一下
Just going to lay down for a second
我觉得我在监狱里
I feel like I'm in a prison
不，巴塞洛缪是故事里的前牢犯
No, Bartholomew's the ex-con in the story
克拉琳达根本都不知道
And Clarinda doesn't even know about it
但丹妮卡知道他的秘密
But Danica's onto him
他们都怪克拉琳达 但丹妮卡会来处理的
They all blame Clarinda but Danica's gonna get to the bottom of it
不，不
No No
对，就是你，克拉琳达
Yes It was you Clarinda
会来处理的
I will get to the bottom of this
你犯了大错
You've made terrible mistakes
是克拉琳达！
It was Clarinda!
哦
Oh
看谁来了
Look who's here
麻醉剂
我们今天聚集在此怀念
We are here today to remember what was lost...
17年前我们失去的
seventeen years ago
你记得吗？
Do you remember?
佩吉跟我
Peggy comes with me
乔伊一半的时间跟我们过
Joy spends half the time with us
我们会带走她的纸森林
We'll take her paper forest
那是乔伊的宝贝 该放在这座房子里
That's Joy's special thing, and it belongs in this house
不，我…
No, I...
乔伊
Joy
乔伊，醒醒！
Joy, wake up!
有人在按门铃
Someone's been ringing the doorbell
杰基！
Jackie!
哦，谢天谢地！是你
Oh, thank God! It's you
怎么了？我担心你，我好久见不到你了
What happened? I'm worried about you I don't see you any more
你没来参加家长会
You don't come to the PTA
你记得我妈妈在水池洗梳子 头发总是把水管堵住吗？
You know how my mom's always clogging the sink with her hair from the brushes?
她房间的水管？
With the pipes in her room?
对，她又这么做了
Yeah She did it again
又一次？
Again?
是啊，我不得不在地板上凿开一个洞
Yes, and I had to bash open a hole in the floor
我妈妈房间的地板上有一个大洞 我已经没钱了
There's a huge hole in the floor of my mother's room and I'm broke
我爸爸工作得很努力 但他最近也诸事不顺
My father works hard He's had some bad breaks
我希望他能找个女朋友 那样他就能搬出地下室
I hope he gets another girlfriend, and he'll move out of the basement
他现在跟托尼一起住在地下室？
He's in the basement with Tony?
是的，他们互相憎恶
Yes And they hate each other
对
Yes
简直糟透了，他们不停地吵架
It's a disaster They won't stop fighting
我不知道
I don't know
你怎么样？家里人怎么样？ 大家都怎么样？
But how are you? How's the family? How is everybody?
大家都还好
Everybody's okay
工作呢？
How's work?
我的工作可有可无
My job, I could take it or leave it
我们怎么了，杰基？
What happened to us, Jackie?
我们曾经梦想过的事情
All the things that we used to dream about
我觉得那离我们越来越远
I feel like they just keep getting farther and farther away
记得最初的那场晚会吗？
Remember the night of the party where everything started?
乐队在演奏
The band was playing
一切都是那么令人兴奋
Everything was so exciting
乔伊，你来了！
Joy, you came!
我好高兴你来了！ 这是我男朋友，安德烈
I'm so glad you came! This is my boyfriend, Andre
–嗨，安德烈 –很高兴见到你
- Hi, Andre - Nice to meet you
安德烈，这是我儿时的朋友乔伊
Andre, this is my childhood friend, Joy
进来啊！
Come inside!
–哇 –来看看我的乐队，会计女孩
- Wow - Check my music class, accountant girl
这是个乐队？
This is a class?
是的！
Yes!
别打开灯，因为我不想看见
Don't turn on the lights 'cause I don't wanna see
妈妈叫我别来
Mama told me not to come
–他们真棒！ –是啊！天才嘛
- They're so good! - They are! The teacher's band
妈妈叫我别来
Mama told me not to come
她说：“不是这样玩的，儿子”
She said, "That ain 't the way to have fun, son"
“不是这样玩的”
"That ain 't the way to have fun"
妈妈叫我别来
Mama told me not to come
–那个光头的家伙是谁？ –我们的音乐老师
- Who's the bald guy? - That's our music teacher
他有所有这些…这是他的房子？
And he has all this... This is his house?
–对，这是他的房子 –哇
- Yeah, this is his house - Wow
他来自委内瑞拉
He's from Venezuela
–那个家伙呢？ –对
- Who is that guy? - Yeah
那是音乐老师的儿子
That's the music teacher's son
哦，我的天
Oh, my gosh
你在跳舞，很好
You're dancing Here you go
我现在在做什么？
What am I doing now?
–你在跳舞 –不
- You're dancing - No
–让我带你参观一下我爸爸的房子 –什么？
- Let me show you my father's house - What?
来，来
Yeah, yeah, yeah
我会成为一名歌手
I'm gonna be a singer
真的吗？
Really?
是的，我要成为下一个汤姆琼斯
Yeah I'm gonna be the next Tom Jones
野心好大，不过只有一个汤姆琼斯
That's a big ambition There's only one Tom Jones
我知道，但你不能被现实吓倒
I know, but you can't let the practical get you down
你要不断地追逐你所爱的事
You gotta keep going to what you love
没错
That's true
那是我爸爸教我的
That's what my father taught me
你呢？
What about you?
我发明了一个狗项圈，想要申请专利 但可能实现不了
I invented a dog collar that I want to get patented, but I don't think it ever will
我在高中是最优等生
I was valedictorian in high school
我考上了波士顿的大学
I got into a college in Boston...
但我现在待在这里 因为我父母正在闹离婚
but I'm staying here because my parents are getting divorced...
我会留下来帮我妈妈
and I'm staying to help my mom
我帮我爸爸的生意做点会计的工作
And I help my dad with business stuff Accountant
可能你的梦想只是暂停一下而已
Maybe your dreams are on hold right now
不是吗？
No?
这么说真不错
That's a nice way of putting it
一些愚蠢的事
This song is going to be in the town musical
这首歌会用在镇子上的音乐剧中
我们该一起来唱
We should sing it together
我知道我站在那 等着你有时间
I know I stand in line Until you think you have the time
来与我共度夜晚
To spend an evening with me
真不错
That's really nice
好，一起来
Okay, go
–不 –好
- No - Okay
如果我们去某处跳舞
And if we go someplace to dance
我知道会有一线机会 你不会离开我
I know that there's a chance You won't be leaving with me
他在我孙女最低落的时候 给她带来了一缕阳光
He gave my girl a spring in her step, just when she needed it
我们要做什么？托尼
What are we doing? T ony
他让她来演音乐剧 她以前从未演过
He got her to do the musical, something she never would have done
我知道我站在那 等着你有时间
I know I stand in line Until you think you have the time
来与我共度夜晚
To spend an evening with me
如果我们去某处跳舞 我知道会有一线机会
And if we go someplace to dance I know that there's a chance
你不会离开我
You won't be leaving with me
然后我们去一个安静的地方 喝上一两杯
And afterwards we drop into a quiet little place And have a drink or two
然后我会说些蠢话，比如“我爱你”
And then I go and spoil it all By saying something stupid like "I love you"
我能从你的眼中看出 你讨厌这不变的古老的谎言
I can see it in your eyes That you despise the same old lies
你昨晚才听过
You heard the night before
你那么聪明，那么漂亮，我只是…
You're so smart, you're so beautiful, I... I just...
你可以嫁给任何人
You could have married anybody
你可以嫁给医生、律师 一个很好的男人，而不是这个…
You could have married a doctor, a lawyer, a nice man instead of this...
我都不知道该怎么叫他
I don't even know what to call this guy
你真的要现在来谈这事吗？
Are you seriously talking about this right now?
为时未晚
It's still not too late
爸爸
Dad
我们走吧
Let's go
考虑一下
Think about it
爸爸！
Dad!
我们是友爱团结的一家
We are a loving family, a solid family
我跟我太太结婚…
I've been married to my wife...
现在我要发言
Now I have a speech
他还没说完，爸爸
He wasn't finished, Dad
现在他说完了
He's finished now
我有两次失败的婚姻
I had two failed marriages
我第一次婚姻的女儿，佩吉
The daughter from my first marriage, Peggy...
和我第二次婚姻的女儿乔伊感情很好
has a lot of tension with the daughter from my second marriage, Joy
我跟乔伊的妈妈度过了 极其糟糕的18年婚姻生活
I was married to Joy's mother for 18 miserable fucking years
爸爸！太刻薄了！坐下！
Dad! That's just mean! Sit down!
但我走出来了
But I got out of all that
我最终遇见了我生命中的阳光，莎伦
And I finally met the light of my life, Sharon
–敬你，宝贝 –爸爸！
- To you, baby - Dad!
你是我爱的人
You're my guy
我敬你
I toast you
爸爸！别这样！
Dad! Stop!
–你能不能不这样？ –鲁道夫，拜托！够了
- Will you stop it? - Rudolph, please! Enough
–你现在高兴了？ –相当高兴，是的
- Are you happy now? - Fairly happy, yes
看我找到了什么
Look what I found
离婚酒杯
The divorce glass
我敬大家
Salud
我给这对新人一半的成功机会
I give these kids 50-50 odds
敬大家，祝你们玩得开心
Salud, everybody Have a good time
托尼，醒醒！
Tony, wake up!
求你了！克里斯蒂还没吃饭 汤米要换尿布
Please! Cristy hasn't eaten, Tommy needs to be changed
哦，克里斯蒂，你在干什么？
Oh, Cristy What are you doing?
–起来，我刚跟你老板说你会去上班！ –你为何要撒谎？
- Get up I just told your boss you're going to work! - But what did you lie for?
–因为你又快要丢掉一份工作了！ –不行，亲爱的，我病了！
- Because you're gonna lose another job! - No, honey, I'm sick!
你没病，你是宿醉！
You're not sick, you're hungover!
那不是我！我是名歌手 那才是我要做的！
That's not who I am! I'm a singer, that's what I do!
你唱歌赚不了钱！
You're not making any money singing!
现在马上上车去上班！
Get in your car right now and go get your job!
你想把我变成另一个人！
You're trying to turn me into someone I'm not!
我受不了了！ 我受不了了，托尼！
I can't do this! I can't do this, Tony!
我快要疯了！
I am losing my mind!
我不想像我父母一样
I don't wanna end up like my family
时光飞逝
Time moves forward
时光倒流
Time moves backwards
时光静止
Time stands still
我跟我的简介一致还是不如我的简介？
Do I live up to my profile or do I fall short?
开玩笑吧？你太棒了，就像 加了朗姆酒的香蕉弗朗焙
Are you kidding? You're a banana flambé with extra rum
你让我非常开心，就像光速飞到月球
You're a trip to the moon on gossamer wings
哇！你好有诗意、好浪漫
Wow! You're so poetic and romantic
是真的！
It's true!
正如我死去的丈夫莫里斯
Just like my late Morris
莫里斯，他是美国人，你是意大利人 你的原名是什么？
Morris Now, he was American and you're Italian, and your name originated how?
我的意大利名叫吉尔特鲁得
My name My Italian name is Geltrude
吉尔特鲁得
Geltrude
然后他叫我“特鲁得” 后来就更美国化，叫“特鲁迪”了
And then he called me "Trude," and then became more American "Trudy"
特鲁迪
Trudy
你带上所有家人来我前夫的船上玩吧？
Why don't you come with your entire family, on my late Morris' boat?
带上孩子们、孙子们
Bring the children, bring the grandchildren
摩托艇类的？
Like a motorboat?
不，是艘近17米长的帆船
No, no, it's a sailboat 55 feet
–哇，好大 –是的
- Wow That's big That is big - Yeah Yeah
好，我很乐意
Yeah, I would love to
我们会带些好吃的、好喝的，一定会很棒
We'd bring some nice food, something to drink, that would be great
好，但不要带红酒 否则会弄脏茶树木甲板
Yeah, but not red wine, because it might stain the teakwood deck
很珍贵的
It's very precious
好，明白，不要带红酒
Okay, understood No red wine
我带了红酒！
I got the red wine!
不，对不起，你不能带红酒上船
No, no, no, I'm sorry, you can't have red wine on the boat
不能带红酒，托尼
No red wine, Tony No red wine
为何？是很好的红酒！
Why? It's a beautiful wine!
为何大歌星会来这？谁邀请他的？
What's Tom Jones doing here anyway? Who invited him?
他来帮我看孩子
He's here to help me with the kids
我带了佩吉来帮忙
I brought Peggy to help
佩吉对我的孩子说我的坏话，所以…
Peggy says mean things about me to my children, so...
我也说了你的好话
I say nice things about you, too
这是很好的酒
It's a beautiful wine
你也有口音！
You have an accent, too!
是的
Yes
你来自哪里，朋友？
Where are you from, paesano?
朋友？请别鼓励他
Paesano? Don't encourage him, please
我来自委内瑞拉，亲爱的
I'm from Venezuela, darling
你知道这首歌吗？
Do you know this song?
我能看出她为何还爱着他！
I can see why she still loves him!
来，上船来
Come on Come on board
–一场灾难将至 –爸爸
- This is gonna be a disaster - Dad
干杯！
Cheers!
我穿了乘船的衣服 但没料到有那么冷
I dressed for boating but I didn't realize how cold it was gonna be
我在米兰遇见我的前夫莫里斯 他为他的泳装产品来参加展会
My late husband Morris, I met him in Milano for a trade show for his swimwear line
他以前总说：“在冬天扬帆
He used to say, "Sailing in the winter...
“正如在生意场的生活”
"is the best comparison to life in the world of commerce"
莫里斯号
哦，不！
Oh, no!
莫里斯的茶树木甲板！
Morris' teakwood deck!
对，干得真不错，真棒
Yeah Grand adventure Great
干得好，大歌星
Nice work, Tom Jones
特鲁迪，我知道那真不幸 可能莫里斯会说：“多棒的冒险啊！”
Trudy, I know that it's upsetting, but wouldn't Morris say, "What a grand adventure?"
对，你说得对，不是大事 他可能正在天堂大笑呢
Yeah, you're right No big deal He's probably laughing up in heaven
我们该用纸杯的
We should have used paper cups
不，那感觉就不一样了
No, but it's not the same thing
你要用好杯子喝好酒
You need a nice glass for a beautiful wine, you know?
哦，天啊
Oh, boy
看，她手上有一片玻璃碎
Look It's a piece of glass right in her hand
你没事吧，亲爱的？
Are you all right, honey?
嗯，她在想事情呢，托尼
Yeah, she's thinking of something, Tony
一个圈，一个连续的东西
One loop One continuous thing
她在自言自语，好奇怪
She's talking to herself It's strange
亲爱的，你该上床睡觉了
Honey, you should go to bed
如果是一个连续的圈，对
If it was all one continuous loop Yeah
嗨，我是图森
Hi, I'm Touissant
图森？这是谁？
Touissant? Who's this guy?
不是找我的，找你的吗？
It's not for me Is it for you?
不，不是找我的
No, it's not for me, man
水管工
The plumber
他来做什么？
What's he here for?
你觉得呢？泰瑞的事
What do you think? Terry
泰瑞的事，哦，泰瑞
Terry Oh, Terry
哦，不，怎么回事？ 这个男人在我房间做什么？
Oh, no, wait What's going on? What is this man doing in my room?
这是…
This is...
–图森 –图森
- Touissant - Touissant
泰瑞，这是图森
Terry, Touissant
我把节目录下来了
Well, I mean, I've taped my show...
这要弄多久？
and then, well, exactly how long is this going to take?
应该不超过一天
Well, it shouldn't take more than a day
那是哪种口音，乔伊？
What accent is that, Joy?
是哪个国家的口音？
What country is that from?
–海地 –海地
- Haiti - Haiti
海地？
Haiti?
那里讲法语和克里奥尔语
It's French and Creole
法语和克里奥尔语
French and Creole
有没有方法… 你能在这挂一个帘子
Well, is there any way... Could you please put a curtain up here...
这样在他干活的时候 我就能进出我的房间和看电视了？
so that I can come and go in my room and watch my show while he's still working?
当然，我有个钉墙机
Of course I have a stapler
谢谢你，先生
Thank you, sir
不用谢，小姐
You're welcome, mademoiselle
小姐？
Mademoiselle?
祝你好运，跟她，还有水管
Good luck in here and good luck with the... that
你去睡觉吧
Why don't you go to bed?
继续上楼梯，去睡觉
Keep going up the stairs Go to bed
我不想睡觉，我不想做那个噩梦
I don't want to go to sleep I don't want to have that horrible dream
别这样！你不可能做同一个梦，从来不会
Come on! You can't have the same dream twice It never happens
–不可能的 –不对
- It's impossible - That's not true
我小时候做了多次佩吉戴面具
I had the Peggy dream so many times when I was younger...
穿长袍的梦
with the masks and the robe
这不合理，不
It doesn't make sense No, no
你不会做同一个梦，可能是…
You can't have the same dream twice Maybe it's the...
鲁迪，她在思考些东西
Rudy, she's thinking about something
可能是个好梦，她在思考问题
Maybe it's a good dream, and she's working something out
我不想思考任何问题，我只想睡个好觉
I don't wanna work anything out I just want a nice, dumb sleep
我们想办法让她睡 给她喝点儿童止咳糖浆
Let's knock her out Give her a children's cough medicine
–会有作用 –安全吗？
- That's what does it - Is that safe?
不，不安全
No It's not safe
过期了
It's expired
给你，喝下去，亲爱的
Go on, there Knock it back, honey
–不要 –好，再来一杯，来啊
- No - Okay, one more Knock it down Come on
–鲁迪！ –照做，托尼
- Rudy! - Do it, Tony
–我不确定 –倒吧，再来一杯
- I don't know - Just do it One more
好，再来一杯
Okay, one more
够了！就这样，我去给她弄杯香甜热酒
Enough with this! That's it I'm gonna make her a hot toddy
那个才是她需要的
That's what she needs
你会把她灌醉的
You're gonna intoxicate her
全是天然的草药，没有效用强的成分
It's all natural, it's all herbal Nothing strong
我被另一个来自瑞士的修道士绑架
I was kidnapped by another monk, who was from Switzerland
这个修道士原是皇家的公爵
And it turned out that this monk was a duke of a royal family
我不该说“原是”，他仍旧是
I shouldn't say "was," because he still is
别管我
Leave me alone
我们不该让她睡在楼梯上
I don't thi nk we should let her sleep on the stairs
我们把她放在沙发上吧？
Let's just put it here in the couch, okay?
17年
Seventeen years
好好想想，我们一直隐藏了
Think about it We've been hiding...
17年
for seventeen years
Seventeen years
17年前我们常造东西
We used to make things Seventeen years ago
然后全停止了，怎么了？
Then, that all stopped What happened?
当你藏起来时，你很安全
When you're hiding, you're safe...
因为人们看不见你
because people can't see you
但藏起来的问题是
But, funny thing about hiding...
你在逃避自己
you're even hidden from yourself
宝贝，怎么了？
Baby, what's the matter?
托尼，你要从地下室搬出去
Tony, you need to move out of the basement
你要自己出去住
You need to get your own house
什么？为什么？
What? Why?
因为我晚上去安吉拉的俱乐部唱歌？
Because I go out at night and sing at Angela's club?
–是因为这吗？ –不是
- Is that it? - No
因为我们已经离婚两年了
Because we've been divorced for two years
我们要向前看
We need to move on
你要搬出去
You need to move out
鲁迪，你也要搬出去
Rudy, you need to move out, too
什么？
What?
现在地下室有更多的空间了
There's more room in the basement for me now
还有另一件事，鲁迪
And another thing, Rudy
明天我想跟你和特鲁迪 在你的办公室开个会
Tomorrow, I would like to have a meeting with you and Trudy at your office...
和她谈谈投资生产我的一个新想法
to discuss her investing in the manufacturing of my new idea
不行
No
我还在了解她，想要爱上她
I'm still getting to know her and falling in love
我不能那么做，我不会那么做
I can't do that I won't do that
制造什么？你在说什么？
And what manufacturing idea? What are you talking about?
我一直都在你身旁，无论发生什么事
I have always been there for you, no matter what
我没有为了上大学离开
I didn't go away to school
我留下来帮你和妈妈办离婚 做你的会计
I stayed to help you and Mom through the divorce and do your accounting
我让你随时来这里住
I let you live here whenever you want...
无论什么原因
no matter what it is
我向你郑重提出还我人情
I am respectfully asking for the favor that you owe me
你扪心自问一下，你知道我是对的
If you look into your heart, you'll know that I'm right
克里斯蒂，我要用你的彩色蜡笔 彩色铅笔和纸
Cristy, I need to use your crayons, your colored pencils and your paper
来我的房间吧
Let's go to my room
你不会相信的
You're not gonna believe this
你记得你推荐的那个水管工吧？
So, you know that plumber that you recommended?
记得，图森
Yeah, Touissant
我雇了他，泰瑞吓死了 完全不知该怎么办
So I hire him, Terry freaks out, completely disoriented
鲁迪之后，八年了 都没有男人进过她的房间
Hasn't had a man in her room for eight years, since Rudy
让我挂了个帘子
Makes me hang a drop cloth
我觉得
The way I look at it...
这是你投资新领域的机会
is that this is an opportunity for you to invest in a new business...
意味着你会赚更多的钱
...that'll mean more money for you
爸爸，告诉里科 把五号机器关掉
Tell Rico, Dad Number five's gotta go off
里科，五号机器，关掉
Rico, number five, no, off
关掉！谢谢你！
Go off! Thank you!
一个标准的把手，135厘米
It's a standard handle, 53 inches
套管和拖把头连接
The sleeve connects to the mop head
这里就有点复杂了
Now, this is where it gets complicated
有一个夹子连接套管和…
There's a clip that connects the sleeve to the...
我都不知道该怎么叫，那个“杯子”
I don't even know what to call it The "cup"
那里连接着拖把头
Which is connected to the mop head
当你把套管拉起，拖把头就会被拉紧
So, when you pull up on the sleeve, the mop head stretches...
不用手触碰就能把它拧干
so you can wring it without ever touching it with your hands
我们只看见了蜡笔画的草图
The only thing we see is this crayon drawings
我们想象不出来
We can't make heads or tails
我们不知道那是什么
We don't know what it is
那拖把不会像头发一样散着吗？ 像绳子一样？
So, the mop doesn't hang loose, like hair? Like a string?
会挂住，但不会散，不像头发
It hangs, but not on loose, open ends like hair
是一个连续的圈
It's one continuous loop
–我不明白 –我不明白
- I don't get it - I don't get it
–我不明白，他来做什么？ –他来做什么？
- I don't get it What's he doing here? - What's he doing here?
他是我孩子的父亲，我的朋友 他来支持我
He is the father of our children, and my friend, and he looks out for me
我们在创造发明
We're doing an invention
干杯
Cheers
好
Right
确实是，克里斯蒂
Yes we are, Cristy
很认真的
It's very serious
重中之重
It's priority
是的
Yes it is
我在帮忙
And I'm helping
是的
Yes you are
在海地就是这样做的
Ça se fait comme ça in Haiti
图森在教我说法语
Touissant is teaching me how to speak French
“勤恳”是这么说的…
And the word for "industrious" is...
对
Yes
一开始我觉得会发生可怕的事
At first I thought maybe something scary would happen...
正如在丹妮卡身上发生的事 她被一个人绑架
like what happened with Danica while she was kidnapped by a man...
其实那个人是个藏在瑞士的皇家贵族
who turned out to be in hiding from the royal family in Switzerland...
然后她就搬去了瑞士
and then she moved to Switzerland
当然，她跟那个人不仅仅是朋友关系
Of course, she befriended that man and more
别想限制我，乔伊
Don't ever try and limit me, Joy
如果你想吃混合辣蔬菜就告诉我
And let me know if you want some of this Chakalaka
说辣蔬菜就行
Chaka Say "chaka"
辣蔬菜
Chaka
很好吃的
It's very good
嘿，洛奇，嘿，汤姆！
Hey, Rocky Hey, Tom!
带她到办公室去
Take her inside the office
–嘿，提诺 –嘿，乔伊
- Hey, Tino - Hey, Joy
我想给你看样东西
I wanted to show you something
你能帮我造这个吗？
So, will you help me figure this out?
我知道它需要焊接 这个部分要能转起来
I know that it has to be welded This part is supposed to twist
1、2、3
1... 2... 3...
4、5、6…
4, 5, 6...
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
38、39、40
38, 39, 40
好了，爸爸，过来抓住这里
All right All right, Dad, come over here and grab this
抓住中间
Grab it right in the middle
好，这样
Okay There
举起来，杰基往下，你明白了？
And go up, Jackie go down You see it?
还没
Not yet
好，这样
All right Here
–现在呢？ –没有
- How about now? - No
你会明白的
Well you're going to
我还未明白，我是说…
I don't see it yet, I mean...
–你们准备好了？ –好了
- You ready? - Yeah
91米的全棉线
300 feet of continuous cotton loops
我画的就是这个
That's what I drew
这就是为什么 我要你投资这个产品，特鲁迪
This is why I would like to ask you for your investment, Trudy
乔伊，莫里斯辛苦工作50年才赚到这些钱
Morris worked 50 years to earn his fortune, Joy
他过世前让我在他床前发誓
Before he passed on to the next world, he made me promise on his deathbed...
我不会轻易浪费他辛苦挣到的
that I would never be neglectful with one dollar of the money...
每一块钱
that he so carefully earned
所以你必须回答莫里斯的 四个跟理财有关的问题
Therefore you have to answer Morris's four questions of financial worthiness
你准备好了吗？
Are you ready?
我想我准备好了
I think so Yes
第一个问题
Question number one:
你在哪里上的高中？
Where did you go to high school?
普兰菲尔德公立高中
Plainfield Public High
第二个问题 你高中念得怎样？
Question number two: Who were you in high school?
我是最优等生
I was valedictorian
学校里最聪明的学生
The smartest student in the school
那很好，是吧？
That's good, right?
也许
Perhaps
乔伊也许是一个聪明的 还未崛起的商人
Joy might be a brilliant, unrealized creator of commerce
但另一方面
But on the other hand...
同样可能的是 她会是一个致命的失败者
it's equally possible that she is a fatally flawed underachiever...
注定要失败、令人失望 以及不能实现期望
doomed to a lifetime of failure, disappointment, unfulfilled expectations
乔伊，你必须承认
You must admit, Joy...
你迄今为止的生活
that your life, to date, makes a stronger case for...
很令人失望
...disappointment
我不在乎这些
I don't care about any of this
这不但冒险 而且在财务上不负责
It's not only risky, but it's fiscally irresponsible...
并且毫无道理
and doesn't make any sense, whatsoever
乔伊这辈子都没做过生意
Joy's never run a business in her life
我过去十年都在打理我爸的修车厂
I've been running my father's garage for the last 10 years
我们的爸爸
Our father
我想要为这个现成的生意
I have ventures that I'm planning to launch here...
找合作投资
at this existing business
在我来找特鲁迪投资前
You never mentioned any of this...
你对这些提都没提过
until I came to Trudy to ask for an investment
莫里斯的第三个问题是？
What's Morris's third question?
你是否准备好
Are you prepared...
在投资的六个月内
within six months of commencing this venture...
产出足够的回报？
to show adequate returns?
我接受你的条件
I accept your terms
别这样做，乔伊
Don't do it, Joy
第四个问题呢？
What's the fourth question?
你在一个房间里 桌上有一把枪
You are in a room, and there is a gun on the table
而房间里的另一个人是你的商业对手
And the only other person in the room is an adversary in commerce
你们二人中只有一人能活下来
Only one of you can prevail
不过，你已经保住了 你的生意和莫里斯的钱
Yet, you have protected your business and Morris's money
乔伊，你会拿起枪吗？
Do you pick up the gun, Joy?
这是个很诡异的问题
That's a very strange question
这个问题一点也不诡异
There is nothing strange about this question at all
这是关乎钱
This is money
你会拿起枪吗？
Do you pick up the gun?
我会拿起枪
I pick up the gun
很好
Good
当我跟我的律师谈话时
I'm going to remember that you said that...
我会记得你说过这话
when I speak to my lawyer
特鲁迪的律师说了什么？
What did Trudy's lawyer say?
他查遍了全球的专利
He did a worldwide patent search
什么是专利？
What's a patent?
专利就像是保护你的想法的法律
A patent is like a law that you get to protect your idea
很多人为他们的想法申请专利
A lot of people patent their ideas...
但只有少数人能实现它们
but only a few of them actually get their ideas made
所以特鲁迪只是想要谨慎行事
So Trudy just wanted to be careful...
乔伊
Joy...
我只想让你知道 图森就要完成他的工作了
I just wanted to let you know that Touissant has almost finished his work
还有…
And, um...
我们真的要给他多找些活干
You know, we really need to find some more work for him
–你想为这房子做更多活？ –对
- You want more work in the house? - Yeah
我得去做另外一个大项目
I have another big job I have to go to
–什么？ –是的
- What? - Yes
–但我们这里确实有问题 –抱歉
- Well, but we have real issues here - Sorry
–妈，我们没钱请他 –嗯…
- We don't have money for that work, Mom - Well...
好吧
Okay
乔伊…
Joy...
妈，你怎么了？
What is happening to you, Mother?
我不知道
I don't know what's going on
你爱上图森了？
Are you in love with Touissant?
我感觉很孤独
I was feeling alone
并且我都没有意识到
And I didn't even realize it, you know?
然后…
And then...
专利搜索的结果呢？
What did the patent search find?
特鲁迪只是想谨慎行事
Trudy just wanted to be careful
这个人找到一个德州的人
And this guy found a man that's in Texas...
他为一个外国人工作
who worked for another guy in another country...
他们有个想法 可能跟我的拖把类似
where they have an idea that might be similar to my mop
哪个国家？
What country?
香港
Hong Kong
那个香港人在德州达拉斯有代理人
The Hong Kong man has a representative in Dallas, Texas
他在德州的代理人跟我的律师很讲理
The Dallas man was very reasonable with my lawyer
嘿
Hey
这个德州人…
So, this guy in T exas...
我们应该向他支付专利保护费，对吧？
We're supposed to pay him a royalty on the patent as a protection, right?
对
Right
以防被要求索赔
T o be safe from any claims
对吧？
Is that correct?
请别再使用“我们”这个字眼
Please stop using the word "we"
这都不是你的钱 也跟你无关
None of this is your money or your business
但这个人同时拥有一家制造工厂
But the same guy also owns a manufacturing plant...
你们说他的要价最便宜？
that you guys say that it's cheaper than any other place?
–是的，在加州 –对
- Yes In California - Yes
一个金属和塑料注塑模具厂
A metal and plastic injection mold factory
好的，所以是同一个人
Okay, so it's the same guy
–他拥有这项专利… –做生意经常都是这样
- He owns the patent... - This happens all the time in business
你找到了最好的合伙人，那很明智
You find the best partner It's smart
他不懂生意
He doesn't understand business He doesn't know business
–对，我是不懂 –我懂生意
- No, no, I'm the first to say that - I understand business
爸爸和我总是为修车厂买配件
Dad and I, we buy parts for the trucks all the time at the garage
莫里斯总是那样做的
Morris did it all the time
一站式采购，那是最便宜的
One-stop shopping It's the cheapest
–但那正常吗？ –他就是那样赚钱的
- But is that normal? - That's how he made his money
–对，正常 –对！
- Yeah, that's normal - Yes!
那个拥有专利的人和拥有工厂的
But is it normal, the same guy who has the patent...
是同一个人，这正常吗？
is the same guy who has the manufacturing?
–再好不过了 –对
- Yeah Make it best - Yeah
–是吗？ –那样最好
- Yeah? - Better if it's that way
好，那律师呢？莫里斯的律师？
Okay, and the lawyer? Right? Morris's lawyer?
–他很好，别找事 –他好得很
- He's good Let's not make trouble - He's very good
但他的专长是服装业，对吧？ 而不是制造业
But he specialized in garment business, no? Not manufacturing business
托尼，见好就收吧
Tony Let's quit while we're ahead
我知道你想让托尼当顾问
I know that you want Tony to be your counselor, if you will...
我尊重那一点
and I will respect that...
在这场商业活动中 托尼和你也应该
as Tony and you should respect what we're proposing...
尊重我们推荐的律师
as the lawyer for this whole business endeavor
好了，配件已经从加州送来
All right The parts have arrived from California...
我们能在这里开始生产
and we can start manufacturing here
我装好了第一把拖把
I have the first assembled mop
我说过它会改良
I told you it was gonna be more refined
的确改良了
And it is
马丁内斯神父来了
Father Martinez is here
你得让那些女士们干起活来
You need to set those women up right now and get going
她们会为这工作而感激你的，乔伊
They're gonna be so grateful for the jobs, Joy
好，我去跟她们谈
Okay All right I'll go talk to those ladies
现在我终于有工作给她们做了
Now I finally have jobs for them
我组装给你们看…
And I'll show you guys how to assemble...
我得承认我有些为你自豪了
I'm a little proud of you I gotta admit it
但第一批货的成本就要高一万五千美金
But, it costs much more than $15,000 to make the first run
我知道，特鲁迪
I know, Trudy
无意冒犯，但那不是我的错
But with all due respect, that actually wasn't my fault
看看，又有账单来了
Look at this More bills
–什么？ –杰哈德发来的另一张账单
- What? - Another bill from Gerhardt
这家伙一直为他的过失向我收钱
This guy keeps billing me for his mistakes
–这是做生意 –不
- That's business - No
我不是这样做生意的
That's not the way I do business
我要给他打电话
I'm calling this guy
帕克制造厂–账单
杰哈德，我不会为这些配件一再付钱
Gerhardt, I'm not gonna keep paying for these parts...
你做了四次才做对
that it's taking you four times to get right
那是你的设计 你得为那些配件付钱
That was your design You have to pay for those parts
模具生产就是这样的
That's mold-making That's the process
我们做出东西来 我的客户都会付钱
My clients pay when we figure it out
那不是我的设计，杰哈德
It was not my desig n, Gerhardt
是你的错误，我不会付钱
It was your mistake I'm not paying it
那是你的设计，你得付钱
That was your design You have to pay
你刚挂掉了他的电话？
Did you just hang up on him?
这家伙本该很好合作 而且成本低廉的
This guy was supposed to be easy and inexpensive
结果他不停地向我们多要钱 我不会付
He keeps overbilling us I'm not paying for it
谁也不许付
Nobody pay it
我要跟这个家伙斗争到底
I'm gonna fight it out with this guy
把它们装好，卖出去
Just assemble them and try to sell them
把它放进你的橱窗 让你的顾客决定
Just put it in your window Let your customers decide
我全家都一直照顾你的生意
My family's been going to you my whole life
听着，大公司花钱买我的货架位
Look, the big companies, they pay me for my shelf space
也许你能把你的拖把卖给大公司
Maybe you can sell one of your mops to those big companies
也许他们会把它摆上我的货架
And maybe they'll put it on my shelf
19块95是挺贵 但你以后再也不用买第二个拖把
It's expensive, at $1995, but it's the only mop you'll ever have to buy
但我不想让人们花20块钱 只买一个拖把
But I don't want people to buy one mop for $20...
之后再也不用买拖把
and never have to buy another mop again
我宁愿让他们不断买我们的五块钱拖把 50次、100次
I'd rather they keep buying our mops at $5, 50 times, 100 times
听着，你没钱又无事可做 你有个点子
Look, you were broke and bored You had an idea
那又怎样？很多人都有点子
So what? Lots of people have ideas
回家吧，拜托，照顾好你的家人
Go home Please, take care of your family
嗨，你想试试新拖把吗？
Hi Would you like to try a new mop?
凯马特
It's the only mop you'll ever have to buy
你这辈子只用买一个拖把
–嗨，你想试试新拖把吗？ –不了
- Hi Would you like to try a new mop? - No
它能自己拧干
It's self-wringing
你可以把拖把头拆下 扔进洗衣机里洗
You can remove the mop head, throw it in the washing machine
–没有细菌 –不了
- No germs - No
不了
No
–不了？ –看看
- No? - Look at that
你想试试吗？试试就好
You want to just try it? You could just try
它能自己拧干，看到了吗？ 没有别的拖把能做到
It can self-wring See? No other mop does this
来试试全新的拖把吧！
Come and try the brand-new mop!
–这是未来的拖把 –不用，谢了
- It's the mop of the future - No, thanks
女士们，想要试试这拖把吗？
Want to try this mop, ladies?
–这是什么？ –小姐你好
- What's this? - Hey, miss
这是全新的拖把
It's a brand-new mop
不用弄脏手就能拧干它
You could wring it without getting your hands dirty
不可能
I don't think so
来试试吧，这是未来的拖把
Come on Try it It's the mop of the future
自己拧干是吧？
Self-wringing, huh?
对
Yeah
好吧，我的确喜欢这个点子
All right I do like the idea of that
我讨厌在拖完浴室地板后 用手去碰拖把头
I hate having to touch the mop head after I get done cleaning the bathroom floor
我总觉得那很恶心
I always think that's disgusting, you know?
恶心死了
It's so gross
哇，真的能拖到 我的泡沫拖把拖不到的边角
Wow It really does get all the corners that my sponge mop won't get
所有这些被我孩子溅得满是果汁的角落
All those crannies where my kids spill their juice
我真的很喜欢，我们买一个吧？
I really like it Can we buy it?
别着急，克里斯蒂
Take it easy, Cristy
哇，太棒了 你的手不用碰到
Wow I mean, that's just amazing You really don't have to touch it
看看
Look at that
你知道怎样让它变完美吗？
You know what would make this perfect...
如果拖把头能拆下来 放到洗衣机里去洗
if you could remove the mop head, put it in the washing machine...
–洗得很干净 –那就太好了
- Really get it clean - That'd be great
–可以的 –什么？
- You can - What?
你说真的吗？
Are you serious?
–这拖把多少钱？ –19块95
- Well how much is this mop? - It's $1995
不，太贵了
No, that's too much
但我是说 如果你这一辈子只需要买一个拖把
But I guess, I mean, if it is the only mop that you ever have to buy...
我是说我们得不断地 买那些五块钱一个的拖把
I mean we keep buying those $5 mops
–嗨，爸爸 –嗨，宝贝
- Hi, Daddy - Hi, sweetie
你记得安吉拉吧？ 还有她的两个哥哥？
You, you remember Angela? And her two brothers, right?
我记得，你们好
I do Hello
–妈妈，有警察 –女士？
- Mommy, the policeman - Ma'am?
我们犯法了吗？
Did we break the law?
–我要没收你的商品 –不，我们要走了
- I'm taking this merchandise - No, no We're leaving We're leaving
–我这次只是警告你 –我们就要离开了
- Now, I'm gonna let you off with a warning - We were just leaving
不，警官
No Sir...
如果顾客们看到这拖把的威力…
If the customers can just see what the mop can do...
如果我再在这里看见你 你会被起诉的！
But if I catch you out here again, you will be prosecuted!
我该去哪里？警官，拜托！
Well, where do I go? Sir, please!
–你不能在凯马特的地盘卖东西！ –那些拖把是我自己做的
- You cannot sell on Kmart property! - I made those mops myself
–我付了钱的，求你们了 –很辛苦才做好的
- I paid for them Please - It took a lot of work
我不会再回来了 但你们没必要拿走我的东西！
I won't come back, but you don't have to take my stuff!
求你们了！
Please!
–你这样做合法吗？ –你跟你女儿一起
- Are you even allowed to do this? - How embarrassing for you...
这个样子多丢脸啊
to be seen here like this with your daughter
–你是什么样的父母啊？ –是啊，托尼
- What kind of parent are you, huh? - Yeah, Tony
–够了 –嘿
- Enough - Hey
嘿，伙计们…
Hey, hey, guys Guys...
–没事了 –走
- All right - Come on
–我们走 –托尼，我们走
- Let's go - Tony, let's go
我来了，我来了
Yeah, I'm coming I'm coming
克里斯蒂，宝贝，没事，你妈妈没事
Cristy, honey, it's okay Your mommy's okay
这蠢东西，这地方快散架了！
This stupid thing This place is falling apart!
不，不
No... No
纽约电话公司 电话服务停止通知
宝贝，电话用不了
Honey, the telephone isn't working
我知道，我刚接到通知
I know I just got the notice
我得去邻居家借用电话 汤米发烧了
I had to go next door to use the phone Tommy's got a fever
汤米发烧了？
Tommy has a fever?
只是感冒、咳嗽 是传染的，所有小孩都得病了
Simple cold with a cough It's going around All the kids have it
谢天谢地，还有暖气
Thank God the heat's still working
妈咪，电话怎么用不了？
Mommy, why isn't the phone working?
因为我欠费了
Because I'm late on paying the bill
–我们会失去房子吗？ –你不要也这样
- Are we gonna lose our house? - Not you too
不，我们不会失去我们的房子
No, we're not gonna lose our house
来，上楼，去洗澡
Come on Get upstairs Get in the bath
听妈妈的话，进浴缸里去
Listen to your mom and get right in that tub
–我不想洗澡 –我不管
- I don't want a hot bath - I don't care
克里斯蒂，进浴缸里去 听妈妈的话
Cristy, you get in that hot bath Listen to your mother
我不想你也生病
I don't want you getting sick too
劳伦威尔斯说你是卖旧拖把的清洁女工
Lauren Wells said you're a cleaning lady and sell used mops
劳拉威尔斯说的？
Lauren Wells said that?
是的，那让我很伤心
Yeah And it really hurt my feelings
首先，即使我是清洁女工，那又怎样？
First of all, even if I was a cleaning lady, so what?
做体力活并不丢人
There's no shame in hard work
其次，我…
And second of all, you know, I'm...
只是想要卖新拖把，不是旧拖把
I'm trying to sell a new mop, not used mops
第三，别因为别人的瞎话伤心
And third of all, don't take any guff from anybody
别让那影响到你
You know, don't let it in
我知道这很难，我很抱歉这事发生了
I know it's hard And I'm sorry that happened
进浴缸里去
Now get in the bath
快睡觉，宝贝
Come on Go to sleep, honey
乔伊？
Joy?
现在不说了，外婆
Not now, Mimi
乔伊，等等，跟我说今天发生了什么事
Joy, wait, wait Just tell me what happened today
我想知道事情的经过 求你了，我想知道
I want to know how it went Please, I want to know
很糟糕
It was a disaster
但你一定不能放弃
But you must never give up
你从小就是天生的…
Ever since you were little, you were born to bear...
天生的什么，外婆？
Born to bear what, Mimi?
失败者？蒙羞者？
Failure? Disgrace?
在我女儿面前被羞辱的人？
Humiliation in front of my daughter?
在这个家里 你天生就从容大度
You were born to be the unanxious presence in the room
我知道我会活到看到你
And I know that I'm gonna live to see you grow...
成为一个天生的好家长
to be the successful matriarch that you were born to be
女性家长…
Matriarch...
成为有勇气的母亲
T o be a mother with courage
连自己的孩子都养不活
Who can't even support her children
宝贝
Sweetheart
你在这里干什么？
What are you doing here?
我有个主意
I have this idea
–我认识一个人 –什么人？
- A guy I know - What guy?
他以前跟我共事过 现在他为一个大零售商做事
He used to work with me And now he works at this big retailer
新型的生意
A new way of doing business
我是说，值得一试
I mean, it's worth a try
你会帮我吗？
You would do that for me?
当然
Of course
他们是美国模范离婚夫妇
They were the best divorced couple in America
相处得比他们还是夫妻时更好
Much better friends than they were husband and wife
我能帮你安排跟他见面
I can get you a meeting with him
在哪里？
Where is it?
但我不明白我们在阿米什区干什么
But I don't understand what we're doing in Amish country
他们连电都没有 他们怎能在电视上销售？
They don't even have electricity out here How could they sell anything on TV?
这跟亚米什人无关
It has nothing to do with Amish people
只是碰巧在这里 我查过了
It just happens to be located here I looked it up
在亚米什区
In Amish country
是阿米什
Amish
什么？
What?
–阿米什 –阿米什
- Amish - Amish
请签名
Sign in, please
我们是来见马弗布里克曼先生的
We're here to see Marv Brickman
好的
Okay
马弗布里克曼，如果我打给 他的办公室，他会知道你是谁吗？
Marv Brickman, does he know who you are if I call his office?
他当然知道
Of course he knows
我们是朋友，我们以前在一起共事
We're friends We used to work together
QVC电视购物网，请稍等
QVC, please hold
但汤姆的数据都错了…
But Tom was wrong about that He was wrong about the numbers...
托尼
Tony
马弗，你好吗？
Marv How are you?
我今天不能跟你谈
I can't see you today
为什么？
Why?
如果你能住在城里，或许明天吧
Maybe tomorrow if you can stay in town
不行，我们还有孩子在家
No, we left the kids at home We can't
我们待不到明天
We can't stay until tomorrow
你不能就这样来就希望能见到谁吧
Listen, you can't just expect to come in here and see someone
嘿，你弄好那个广告事宜了吗？
Hey, did you take care of that advertising thing?
–是的 –很好
- Yes, I did - Good All right
怎么了？
What's going on here?
–这是我的好朋友，托尼 –托尼马兰纳
- This is my good friend, Tony - Tony Miranda
我们一起在金宝汤公司工作过
We worked together at Campbell's
尼尔沃克
Neil Walker
–这是他的前妻 –很高兴见到你
- And this is his ex-wife - Good to meet you
–乔伊 –嗨，尼尔
- Joy - Hi Neil
她是个发明家
She's an inventor
她今天想跟你谈两分钟 尼尔，要不算了
She wanted two minutes of your time today, but, Neil, don't worry about this
–要不明天吧 –这样吧
- Maybe tomorrow - You know what?
要不趁销售团队还在，进来五分钟吧
Why don't you come in for five minutes while the sales group's still here
–好，帮我拿着包 –尼尔，你肯定？
- Okay Hold my bag - Neil, are you sure?
–是的 –好，当然了
- Yeah - Yeah, absolutely
谢谢你
Thank you
–都拿好了？ –是的
- Got everything? - Yeah
太棒了，谢谢你，伙计
Great Thank you, man
谢谢你
Thank you
请告诉我们你的名字
So tell us your name, please
我叫乔伊
I'm Joy
今天你想给我们展示什么？
And what would you like to show us today?
我发明了一个自己拧干拖把
I have a self-wringing mop
这…
Just...
要帮忙吗？
Do you need some help?
不用
No No, no
好了
All right
水泼我鞋上了
That's my shoe
哦，天啊，真对不起，先生
Oh, my goodness I am so sorry, sir
袜子都湿了
Sock's wet
你介意吗？
Do you mind?
对不起
Sorry
那是塑料吗？
Is that plastic?
是的
Yes
阿诺德，要不你来试试吧，可以吗？
Arnold, why don't you give it a try? Is that okay?
当然
Yes, of course
把它浸下去
Just dunk it
–我沾一下？ –是的
- I dip it? - Yes
然后扭一下？
And then I... twist it?
你要先拉一下
But you pull... You have to pull it first
–先拉再扭 –你扭之前要先拉
- Pull it and twist it - You got to pull it first before you twist it
–我在拉然后… –先拉再扭
- I'm pulling it and... - Pull and twist
再扭
And I am twisting it
先拉再扭，就像做爱一样
Pull and twist, just like when you're on the road
我们不是有意冒犯你，乔伊 这是我们忙了一整天了，快下班了
We don't mean to be disrespectful, Joy It's the end of a long day for us
我觉得我该来介绍一下自己
I feel like I want to tell you a little bit about who I am
因为我觉得你不知道你现在在哪里
Because I have a feeling you don't know exactly where you are right now
我说得对吗？
Am I right?
十个月前
T en months ago...
一个叫巴里迪勒的人从洛杉矶给我打电话
a man named Barry Diller called me from Los Angeles
他开办了一个电视网络，福斯电视频道
He started a television network Fox television channel
之前他还运营着20世纪福斯电影公司
And prior to that, he ran 20th Century Fox, among other studios
他收购了宾州兰开斯特
And he acquired a little cable channel...
一家小型有线电视频道
right here in Lancaster, Pennsylvania
他雇了我来经营
And he hired me to run it...
这个全新的理念
as a bigger idea
我来自密歇根州的底特律
Now, I'm from Detroit, Michigan
我曾经营美国最大、最实惠
I ran America's largest, most affordable...
最成功、最在乎性价比的零售连锁企业
successful, value-driven retailer
这个连锁企业叫做凯马特
Chain called Kmart
之前我负责为凯马特采购
Prior to that, I was a buyer for Kmart
再之前，我负责七间不同的凯马特商店
And prior to that, I managed seven separate Kmart stores
我决定在我们的商店里销售哪些产品
I decide what products we let into our stores here...
让它们进入千家万户 全天候为我们尊贵的客人服务
into people's homes, 24 hours a day, for our valued customers
我会很小心、谨慎地选择
I choose very carefully and very conservatively
我一天的大部分时间都是 在婉拒像你这样的提案
I spend most of my day deflecting incoming shots from people like yourself
你看见那个图表了吗？
You see that chart?
即日收入
这条绿线每个月或平或升
This green line either rises or stays the same each month
我选的产品都不会出问题
There's no problem with my product choice
你知道QVC代表什么吗，乔伊？
Do you know what QVC stands for, Joy?
不知道
No, I don't
质量、价值、便利
Quality, Value, Convenience
我卖人们可以支付的产品 但我不卖质量差的产品
I sell product affordably, but I don't sell cheap product
你的拖把是塑料做的 而且看起来很奇怪
And your mop is plastic and it looks strange
说实话，我不懂什么图表
I don't know anything about charts
或是
Or...
生意经
...business, frankly
但我会在家打扫卫生
But I do clean my own home
我发明这个拖把
And I made this mop...
是因为它比市面上的任何拖把都好
because it is better than anything else out there
请给我一个机会
Please give me a chance
我喜欢用塑料来造
I like that it's plastic...
因为手拿着很轻，就像没拿东西
because it's so light in my hands, it's like nothing
而且比市面上任何一个拖把的吸水性都好
It's also ten times more absorbent than any other mop on the market
为什么？
Why?
因为用的是我自己缠的 91米连续的全棉线
Because of 300 feet of continuous cotton loop that I looped myself
对于一个小小的拖把头来讲
That is an enormous amount of absorbent cotton...
那是数量极多的吸水棉
on a very small mop head
现在我已经拖完洗手间了 我都没拧过一次拖把
Now I'm done with the bathroom, and I haven't wrung the mop once
我来问你个问题
Let me ask you a question
你会用这个拖把
Would you take this mop...
这个拖过洗手间
where you were just cleaning the bathroom...
马桶旁、满是细菌的拖把
and around the toilet, and all of those germs...
去拖厨房吗？
and take it into the kitchen...
你的家人会在那里吃饭 你会在那里喂孩子
where your family eats, where you feed your children?
我把拖把头放进洗衣机去洗
I take this mop head, I put it in the washing machine...
出来后就像新的一样
it comes out clean like new
其他的拖把就做不到
You can't do that with any other mop
–所以… –好了
- So... - Stop
下周你能生产出五万把这样的拖把吗？
Can you make 50,000 of these mops by next week?
我想可以
Yeah, I think so
大卫塞尔兹尼克，移民后裔
David Selznick, the son of immigrants...
娶了俄克拉荷马州的詹妮弗琼斯 一位美国甜心
married Jennifer Jones from Oklahoma, America's sweetheart
这显现出，在美国
That just goes to show you that in America...
门不当户不对的结合是很常见的事
the ordinary meets the extraordinary every single day
托马斯，你想说什么？
Thomas Where are you going with that?
你想要的那条紧身裤
The skinny pants you wanted
我从没说过“紧身裤” 我说的是“大礼帽”，经典装束
I never said "skinny pants" I said, "stovepipe" Classic look
我听成“紧身裤”了
I heard "skinny pants"
你知道我有多爱大礼帽
You know how much I love the stovepipe
–大礼帽，经典，明白了 –明白了
- Stovepipe Classic Got it - Got it
–好吧，我们用大礼帽 –谢谢
- Fine, we'll go for stovepipe - Thank you
看到这些人了吗？我跟他们说了很多次了 他们还是不明白
See those guys? I told them so many times and they still don't understand
一位智者曾经说过
A very smart guy once said...
“一件事情你跟别人讲一遍，他们不会听 讲四遍，他们还是不听
"You tell somebody something once, they don't listen You tell somebody four times, they don't listen
“讲到第九遍的时候，他们才会听”
"By the ninth time you say it, they begin to hear you"
这就是我们要工作24小时的原因
That's why we're on 24 hours a day
这就是我得跟这帮人说大礼帽的原因
That's why, with the people who I have to tell about the stovepipe
化妆间放音乐？
Music in the makeup rooms?
对，我觉得这样有气氛，托德
Yeah, I thought it'd give a sense of place, Todd
但如果你不想的话，随时可以关掉
But if you don't want it, you can always turn it down
你是我们最棒的销售员，托德
You're our biggest seller, Todd
只要你觉得舒服就好 我们就在乎你
Whatever you need to make you comfortable You're who we care about
你是我们最棒的销售员
You're our number-one seller
–什么？ –哦，不
- What? - Oh, no
他是你们最棒的销售员？
He's your number-one seller?
不不不，辛迪，别这样 你知道我们爱你的
No, no, no Cindy, please You know that we love you
哦，老天啊
Oh, for heaven sake
她一向缺乏职业素养 显而易见，她就是嫉妒
She's never had a professional attitude Clearly, she's jealous
但是你能帮我个忙吗？ 和她成为朋友
But could you do me a favor? Make her your friend
你能帮我这个忙吗，托德？ 拜托了？
Could you just do me that favor, Todd? Please?
为了我？
For me?
–可以，先生 –谢谢
- Yes, sir - Thank you
这是乔伊，她有个不可思议的拖把 我们下周会介绍
This is Joy She has a very exciting new mop that we're gonna introduce next week
我想让你介绍，你是我的最佳人选
I would like you to launch it You're my first choice
一个拖把？
A mop?
你想让我介绍一个新产品？
You want me to bring this newborn into the world?
你要介绍的这个新产品是我倾其所有
That newborn that you're holding is every cent, every dollar, even debt...
才研发出来的
that I've ever made
倾其所有？
Every cent you've ever made?
没错
That's right
给我太大压力可不好
That kind of pressure is not helpful
–什么？ –不
- What? - No
这也不符合我推销的技巧
It's not part of my process, either
哦
Oh
–托德 –我不是想给你压力，托德
- Todd... - I didn't mean to pressure you, Todd
托德
–表演者会很挑剔 –他非常敏感
- Performers can be finicky creatures - He's very sensitive
他是我们最棒的销售员 他的销售额高到
He is our number-one seller He is selling everything through the roof...
我们闻所未闻
in numbers we've never seen before
我很严肃对待
I take it very seriously
我把推销产品给千家万户视为荣幸
I see it as a privilege that we have to go into people's homes
我鄙视对此有异议的人
And I despise anybody who's cynical about that
杰克华纳对此没有异议 达里尔扎努克没有异议
Jack Warner wasn't cynical about that Darryl Zanuck wasn't cynical about that
尼尔沃克也没有异议
And Neil Walker is not cynical about that
我带你去看舞台
Let me show you the stage
我相信，有一天
I believe eventually, one day...
电视节目会围绕着普通民众的生活
television will even be by and about actual regular people
甚至电脑也如此，全天候的播放
Maybe even on computers, 24 hours a day
谁都说不准 以前没人想过会有互联网
Who knows? Nobody thought this network would be real
而如今却如此发达了
And here we are
–对了，库存很多 –什么…
- By the way, stock's going through the roof - What...?
得小心琼的狗
Must be mindful of Joan's dog
谁是…谁是琼？
Who's... Who's Joan?
谢谢你，亲爱的
Thank you, darling
在男人的天下穿成这样 你永远不会成功
You're never gonna make it in a man's world dressed like that
皮普先生，你差点被挤成皮普煎饼了
Mr Peepers, you were almost a Peepers pancake
这是一个有四、五个布景的圆形舞台
It's a round stage that has four or five different sets that rotate...
会根据我们推销的产品在规定的时间旋转
depending on what we're selling at a given moment
这个扣环是项链的一部分，看到了吗？
The clasp is part of the necklace See?
看看这个扣环的质量 我们的质量就是如此好
Look at the quality in this clasp That's what we do
精益求精
Absolutely exquisite
琼和辛迪上了 看看这个
Here comes Joan and Cindy Watch this
这些人是主角
These guys are major
琼是天生的推销员
Joan's the original seller
如果你刚开始收集珠宝 你能买到比这更好的吗？
If you're just starting your jewelry wardrobe, can you do anything better than this?
黑色、金色与珍珠的混搭
You're gonna mix in your blacks, your golds, your pearls
–该有的全有了 –全有了
- Everything - Everything
看到它和这桃色的裙子有多搭了吗？
Look at it against the peach Okay?
–瞧瞧 –适合早上
- Look at that - Morning
–瞧瞧 –绿色，适合下午
- Look at that - Green Afternoon
–瞧瞧，黑色，晚上 –黑色，适合晚上
- Look Black, night - Black, evening
–当然适合晚上了 –有比这更优雅的吗？
- Of course at night - I mean, can you be more elegant?
可见它实用又优雅
So it's functional Elegant
你可以单独佩戴 你可以戴着它…我喜欢的一点…
You can wear it alone You can wear it... What I love...
看到了吗，明星和人们总会犯这个错误
See Stars and people, they always make the mistake
他们觉得脸才是重要的 并非如此
They think it's about the face, but it's not
手才是重要的
It's about the hands
因为人们要用到手
Because that's what people use
他们用手拿着他们在乎的东西
They hold things they care about
她的手会成为他们的手
And her hands are gonna become their hands
会成为他们
And that becomes them
之后是他们的声音 他们的眼睛
And then their voice, and then their eyes
明星总是犯这个错
Stars always make the mistake
手和声音才是至关重要的 才是精髓
It's really about the hands and the voice That's the heart of it
J-6276号
Number J-6276
价值100美元
A $100 value
它们多惊艳呀！
Are they not phenomenal?
–看着 –它们可以成为你的
- Now watch this - These can be yours
–辛迪马上就要说… –但你要现在就打电话订购
- Cindy's gonna lay this down right... - But you need to call in right now
3999美元
$3999
…现在！
...now!
你需要它，你可以得到它
You need this You can get this
不过你得现在就打电话
You need to call right now, though
–我被告知数量有限 –看看打进来的电话
- I'm being told we have limited quantity left - Watch the calls come in
看着，电话进来了
Watch them Here they come
3999美元的价格，你或许该多买几条
For $3999, you might as well get several
电话现在进来了
Calls coming in now
电话，电话
Calls Calls
电话，电话，电话，电话
Calls Calls Calls Calls
看着这个统计 我保证能卖出两万多条
Look at the count I guarantee we're gonna go over twenty
这些是符合联邦贸易委员会规定的 这些是合法的
Those are FTC standards Those are legal
这些数字还在增多，你看好了… 这些是真实的销售量，乔伊
Those are coming in Keep your eyes... Those are actual sales, Joy
线路忙吗？
Lines are busy?
–排满了吗？ –满了
- Is the queue full? - Queue's full
好，我们现在要打一个电话
Okay We need a phone call right now
当他们打不进来的时候 我们要让他们继续看节目
When they can't call through, we gotta keep them watching
打通了吗？打通了吗？
Did we get a call? Did we get a call?
好，知道了
Okay Got it
保持通话，现在进电话
Keep this going Phone call right now
等等！ 有人打电话进来了！有人打电话进来了！
Wait, wait, wait! We have a caller! We have a caller!
来自科罗拉多州的莎朗，嗨，莎朗
Sharon from Colorado Hi, Sharon
嗨，莎朗
Hi, Sharon
辛迪和琼！ 我简直不敢相信在和你们通话！
Cindy and Joan! I can't believe I'm talking to you!
你对你的项链还满意吗？
Are you happy with your necklace?
这些项链太精美了，也不会过时
These necklaces are so gorgeous and timeless
–我的曾祖母就有这样的项链 –对对，接着讲
- My great-grandmother had things like this - Y es, yes Keep it going
买到这些我真是太激动了
I am so excited to have these
继续，对对对
Keep it going Y es Y es Y es
给你妈妈买一条 给你姐妹买一条
Get one for your mother Get one for your sister
看统计，乔伊，乔伊
Watch the counter, Joy Joy
–买它不会后悔的 –对，不会
- You will not regret owning this - No, you will not
看到这些数字了吗？
See those numbers?
我们要达到两万五千了
We're gonna wind up at 25,000
辛迪知道如何销售
Cindy knows how to close it
哇
Wow
我想要你回家，给你的律师打电话
Okay, I want you to go home, I want you to call your lawyer
看下你的合同
Look at your contract
确保工厂已经准备就绪
Make sure your product factory is in line
–好吗？ –好的
- Okay? - Okay
好的，祝你好运，祝你顺利 我们走吧，我送你出去
Okay, Godspeed, good luck Here we go I'll walk you out
鲁迪的卡车和车身
你不能指望特鲁迪在你还欠她 一万八美元来生产仍未卖掉的拖把时
You can't expect Trudy to write a check for $200,000 for 50,000 mops...
会为你再开出二十万美元的支票 去生产还没卖出去的五万个拖把
when you already owe her $18,000 to make mops you haven't even sold yet
你明白有商家想在电视上卖我的拖把吗？
Do you understand that there is a business that wants to sell my mop on television?
会大卖的
It's going to sell
好把，如果你坚信这点的话 你出一半的钱
Fine You feel so strongly about it, you put up half the money
没错，你也要分担财务风险才算公平
Yes It's only fair that you share the financial risk, too
她如何做到？她一无所有，她没钱
How's she gonna do that? She's got nothing She's got no money
你们想我把房子再抵押一次吗？
What, do you want me to take out a second mortgage on my house?
他们想我把房子再抵押一次
They want me to take out a second mortgage on my house
再抵押一次？
A second mortgage?
但那房子，孩子们，乔伊
But the house, the kids, Joy
会怎么样，乔伊？你怎么处理？
What's gonna happen, Joy? How would you do that?
我不知道
I don't know
–嗨，你好吗？ –嗨
- Hey How you doing? - Hey
你知道我从你还是个小女孩起 就一直透过栅栏观察你了吗？
You know I've been watching you through that fence since you were a little girl?
–知道 –我看着你长大
- Yeah - I've been watching you grow up
–嗨，听着 –什么？
- Hey, listen - What?
你觉得如果我…
You think it would be okay if I...
–你想打几发吗？ –想
- You wanna fire a few rounds? - I do
好，或许会让你好受些
Yeah Might make you feel better
谢谢，我觉得会
Thank you I think it will
–你知道怎么拿枪吗？ –对对对
- You know how to hold it? - Yeah Yeah, yeah
好，当然
Okay Sure
好
Good
开始了！哦，老天
This is it! Oh, my gosh
准备好 这绝对会给所有家有地板或浴室的人的
Get ready This is definitely gonna change the holidays...
假期生活带来改变
for anyone who has a floor or a bathroom...
因为这是我们几年来 最令人激动的新型家用产品
because we have the most exciting new home product in years
对！
Y eah!
这是一款新型会自己拧干的拖把
This is the new self-wringing mop
行了，行了
Okay, okay, okay!
新的家庭标配，就在这里
It's the new standard in homes, right here
让我们来看看，由QVC独家销售
Let's take a look at this This is brought to you only by Q VC
这是非常柔软又吸水的棉布
Now, this is clearly extremely soft and absorbent cotton
我们试试
There we go
就用这个，然后你
You just take this, and you...
开始
start...
我不确定，这比看起来要难用
I'm not sure This is a little trickier than it looks
奇迹拖把–有这个拖把就够了！ 节日期间的完美伴侣
放到…
Put it...
我的胳膊被弄湿了
Well, it's getting my arm wet, here
我们这下卖不出去了
Let's see We got no sales here
发生什么了？
What happened?
有电话进来了？
Is there a call?
所以…所以没有电话
So there... So there are no calls
好吧
All right
我们一个也没卖出去 所以我们该这样
And we do not have any sales still so here's what we 're gonna do
我们的节目继续 现在我们的节目继续
We 're gonna move on Now, we 're gonna move on
辛迪会和前《鹰冠庄园》和 《豪门恩怨》演员萨日娜金布尔聊聊
Cindy is gonna talk to Sarina Kimball, former star from Falcon Crest and Dynasty...
她会和我们聊聊她出的新长袍
and she is gonna tell us all about her new line of gowns
这是我的特殊场合长袍
These are my special occasion gowns...
“特殊”形容的多好
"Special" How apropos
是根据我在拍《豪门恩怨》 以及《鹰冠庄园》时的生活设计的
...that were inspired by all of the times that I was in Dynasty and Falcon Crest
真是太棒了
That is absolutely amazing
我想来个特写镜头，看看这些
I want you to pan in Look at these
–看看这些细节 –看看这些细节
- Look at the detail - Look at the detail
看看其中的价值
Look at the value in that
你觉得有多少个亮片？
About how many sequins would you say that is?
就这样了？
That's it?
–没有了吗？ –没了，结束了
- That's all? - No, it's over
也太短了
That's how fast it happens
不，他们会再给她一次机会的
No, they're gonna give her a second chance
不，他们不会再给她一次机会
No, they're not gonna give her a second chance
不会再有了
That's not what's gonna happen
他们会再给她一次机会的
They're going to give her a second chance
–你们为什么都那么消极？ –他们会的
- Why do you have to be so negative? - They will
二十万美元！
$200,000!
五万根拖把
50,000 mops
这条是我的最爱
Now, this is easily one of my favorites
她穿着黑色和金色…
She's wearing the black and gold...
乔伊
Joy
喂？
Hello?
5107个亮片…
5,107 sequins for...
听好了，多少钱？
Get this How much?
299美元
$299
我很遗憾产品没卖出去
I'm sorry the product didn't sell
那人都不知道在干什么，尼尔
That man didn't know what he was doing, Neil
不是他的问题，乔伊 是产品的问题
Well, it wasn't the man, Joy It was the product
我生产了五万根拖把，是你叫我这么做的
I made 50,000 units because you told me to
我抵押了我的房子 我欠了20万美元债，还有更多
I mortgaged my house, I'm in $200,000 of debt More
这是你的生意，你的债
Well, it's your business It's your debt
我们会补偿最多三分之一的损失 如果你看了合同的话
And we indemnify up to a third, if you read your contract
说实话，这都很难争取到
To be honest, that's even gonna be hard to get
尼尔，你要再给我们一次机会
Neil, you gotta give us another chance
我很抱歉，乔伊
I'm so sorry, Joy
我不能向上级这样提议，不能
I just can't bring it to my boss I can't
我不接受你的答复
I can't accept your answer
我办不到，我不接受
I can't, and I won't
乔伊，你得让特鲁迪把损失写进 破产报告里
Joy, you have to let Trudy report this loss in bankruptcy...
否则她会失去更多钱
because otherwise she's gonna hemorrhage even more money
你也得申请破产
You have to file, too...
因为你抵押了你孩子们的未来 你输了
because you mortgaged your children's future and you lost...
你得应对这个结果
and you have to prepare yourself for that
你得申请破产
You have to file for bankruptcy
我警告你很多次了，乔伊！
I warned you so many times, Joy!
爸爸，我警告你不要花她的钱！
Dad, I warned you to not spend her money!
拜托！你一开始就跟她唱反调，佩吉！
Come on! You've been plotting against her from the very beginning, Peggy!
现在我们破产了，托尼！
Now we 're bankrupt, Tony!
我在和我们的律师开会
I'm in a meeting with our lawyers
你这是干什么？
What do you think you're doing?
“回家去，乔伊，看看电视上的数字
"Go home, Joy, and watch the numbers roll in on television
“做五万根拖把
"Make 50,000 mops...
“欠了一大笔债，包括你的房子”
"borrowing and owing every dollar, including your home"
可以处理得更好的
It could have been handled better
我让托德再试一次
I'll let Todd have another shot
我不想让托德或其他人试
I don't want Todd or anyone else to try it
应该让我来
It should be me
我们不让普通人上节目的
We don't have regular people
都是让明星或推销模特来卖产品
We have celebrities or spokesmodels do the selling
我告诉过你的
I told you this
是谁给你演示拖把的？
Who showed you the mop?
是谁推销给你的？是谁教你用的？
Who sold it to you? Who taught you how to use it?
是谁在你认为这拖把一无是处之后 说服你的？
And who convinced you that it was great after you thought it was worthless?
不好意思，能让我们谈一下吗？
Excuse me, can you give us a second?
跟我来
Come with me
你上过电视吗？ 你在电视镜头前自在吗？
You ever been in front of a TV camera? You comfortable in front of a TV camera?
因为当你站上舞台，灯光 镜头和人都会静止
Because when you get there, there's lights and there's camera, and people freeze up
你跟我说过，大卫塞尔兹尼克，移民后裔
You said to me that David Selznick, the son of immigrants...
娶了詹妮弗琼斯 一个俄克拉荷马州的美国甜心
married Jennifer Jones, an all-American girl from Oklahoma...
因为在美国，所有种族和阶层
because in America, all races and all classes...
都能去追求和把握任何一个机会
can meet and make whatever opportunities they can
这就是你把产品卖给千家万户时的感觉
And that is what you feel when you reach into people's homes with what you sell
你是这么说的
You said that
你觉得呢？看起来很棒，对吧？
What do you think? Looks great, right?
对对对，好看
Yeah Yeah, yeah Beautiful
很时髦，很经典
Very vogue, very classic
好了，如果你下次再来… 洛里？洛里？
All right, if you come back next time... Lori? Lori?
我就想让你把头发放下来点 就像这样，如果她下次再来的话
I just want you to just put the hair a little bit forward, just like that, if she comes back again
行吗？不要用梳子，不要梳子
Okay? Not with the comb, not with the comb
–试试黑色 –好的
- Try the black - Okay
行吗？
Okay?
会很完美的
It's gonna be perfect
更衣室D
哇
Wow
很美，你觉得呢？ 你感觉怎么样？
Beautiful What do you think? How do you feel?
我只想做一个改动，你不介意吗？
I'd like to change just one thing Would you mind?
–行啊，给我个惊喜吧 –小改动
- Okay, surprise me - Small thing
我会让你惊喜的
I'll surprise you
好啊，来吧
Okay, surprise me
她要做什么小改动？
What would the small thing be that she changes?
什么？
What?
你全换掉了
You undid the whole thing
这才是我
This is me
这才是你？
This is you?
你和你进来时穿得一样
You've got the exact same outfit you had when you came in here
我穿了衬衫和裤子
I wear a blouse and I wear pants
这就是我
That's who I am
我想以自己的形象上节目
I want to go on as me
以你的形象上节目
Gonna go on as you
我希望你能行
I hope you make it back
琼，辛迪，祝乔伊好运
Joan, Cindy Say good luck to Joy
–哇 –哇
- Wow - Wow
你看起来很棒，祝你今天好运
You look great Good luck today
–谢谢 –祝你好运
- Thank you - Good luck
这就是她，她就是这样的形象
That's her, that's how she is
衬衫和…她该穿裙子的 她有对美腿
Blouse and... She should be in a skirt She's got nice long legs
拍她的腿
Show her legs
祝你好运
Good luck
琼里弗斯想让我穿裙子 但我就穿裤子
Joan Rivers wants me in a skirt, but I'm gonna do pants
随你便吧
Do what you want to do
来吧，我们上楼
Come on, let's go upstairs
你紧张吗？
Are you nervous?
紧张
Yes
做自己就好
Just be yourself
记住，手才是重点
Just remember, it's all about the hands
我们开始吧
Here we go
准备…舞台开转！
Ready... Stage is moving!
家用产品375号，三、二…
Household product 375 in three, two...
你在干吗？拜托
What are you doing? Come on
说啊！说啊！
Go! Go!
她僵住了
She's freezing
不好意思，这些灯光太刺眼了
Sorry, these lights are so bright
没人告诉你这些灯光有多刺眼… 尼尔告诉过我
Nobody tells you how bright these lights... Well, Neil did tell me
尼尔是我在这里的上司
Neil is my boss Here
我应该感谢他让我上台
I should thank him for letting me be up here
–抱歉 –你是乔伊
- Sorry - You're Joy
我是乔伊
I am Joy
说点什么呀！ 聊拖把！
Just say something! Talk about the mop!
哦，我的天！
Oh, my God
我们得做点什么
We have to do something
有电话进来了吗？
Do we have a call?
–我们能转电话进来吗？ –有人打进来
- Could we go to a call? - We have a call
–友好的吗？ –友好的
- It's a friendly call? - It's a friendly call
好，播吧，播吧
Okay Take it Take it
乔伊，我们有电话进来了
Joy, we have a call
有电话了？怎么会？
A call? How did that happen?
好了，我们有电话进来了
Well, we have a call
嗨，来自纽约的乔安娜
Hi Joanne from New York
来自纽约的乔安娜
Joanne from New York
我们有一通纽约的乔安娜打来的电话
We have a call coming in from Joanne from New York
是的，我打来是想说我想要 一个拖地时不需要拧的拖把
Yeah, I'm calling in because I would love a mop that I don't have to touch when I wring it
我拖碎玻璃的时候会弄伤手
You know, my hands get raw and when I mop broken glass...
一拧拖把就会割伤我的手
and I wring the mop, I cut my hands
你以前拧拖把割伤手过吗？
Do you ever cut your hands when you're wringing?
乔安娜，你这样说很有趣
Joanne, that is so funny that you said that
我就是这样才想到发明这款拖把的
That is actually exactly how I was inspired to invent this mop
满地都是碎玻璃 我有两个孩子，还有父亲，我…
There was glass shattered everywhere I was with my two kids, with my father, and I...
我每次拧拖把的时候，手都会被玻璃割伤
Every time I would wring the mop, I would get glass shards in my hands
老式的拖把吸水性也差
And the old mop just wasn't very absorbent
所以我去我女儿房间，借了她的蜡笔
So I went to my daughter's room, and I borrowed her crayons...
我就设计了这款拖把
and I designed this mop
你把镜头放低点，对，就这样
Make sure you get down there Yeah, that's it
这是塑料做的，所以很轻，但非常耐用
It's made of plastic, so it's lightweight, but very durable
特写，手部特写
Go in Go in to the hands
吸水性极好
It's extremely absorbent...
有91米的连续的全棉线
with 300 continuous cotton loops...
是我自己缠的
that I looped myself when I designed it
–多少钱？ –1995美元
- How much is it? - It is $1995
价格我很满意，我想要买一堆
I like that price I want a whole bunch of them
谢谢
Thank you
H375，是货号
H375 That's the order number
家用产品编号375
Household item 375
我向你保证…
I guarantee you...
就在这里，保持住
That's it Stay right there
…你在市面上可找不到 第二根像这样的拖把
...you are not going to find another mop like this that exists
如果有的话，我早就会买了 我也不会割伤手了
If there was, I would have bought it and I wouldn't have cut my hands up
你只要拧一次就能拖完整个厨房 想象一下吧
You can get across the whole kitchen with one wring Just imagine that
看好了
Watch this
巧克力糖浆
Chocolate syrup
拍糖浆，拍糖浆
Go the syrup Go the syrup
婴儿食品 在我家常洒得到处都是
Baby food A very big spill at my house
对我来说是很常见的污渍
Very common spill for me
不，用手，用手
No Hands, hands
最大的区别是 我现在不用碰这个恶心的拖把头了
Now, the biggest difference, I don't have to touch this disgusting mop head
市面上没有第二款拖把
There's not another mop on the market...
有吸水性这样强的全棉线
that has as much absorbent cotton as this mop right here
我向你保证，你不会后悔也不会退货
And I guarantee you, there will be no regrets, no returns
我一生中几乎每天都要拖地
I have been mopping for most of my life, every single day
电话进来了！
Phones are ringing!
这根拖把让我的生活 有了翻天覆地的变化
I cannot tell you how much this mop has changed my life
–电话进来了！ –有电话进来了！
- Phones are ringing! Phones are ringing! - The phones are ringing The phones are ringing
说
Go
这将会是圣诞假期里最棒的拖把
This is gonna be the greatest mop to have around Christmas time...
当你全家都来
when you have family over...
我是两个孩子的母亲 家里经常有东西洒地上
I am a mother of two There is just spill after spill
家人来做客时
Family comes to town
你只要拧一次就能拖干净整个厨房
You can mop your entire kitchen with one wring!
哦，我的天！两万九千个！
Oh, my God! 29,000!
这太不寻常了！
This is very special!
我还没告诉你们我个人最喜欢的一个功能
I haven't even told you about my personal favorite feature...
就是可拆式拖把头
which is the removable mop head...
我就能把拖把头放进洗衣机 洗完就跟新的一样
that I can put into the washing machine and it will come out clean as new
太好了！太好了！
Yes! Yes!
我的天，数字还在不断增大！
Oh, my God, these numbers keep climbing!
谢谢，我…
Thank you I...
对，就这样，继续
Yes, that's right Keep it going
谢谢
Thank you
这是市面上最吸水的拖把，它很轻
This is the most absorbent mop on the market It's lightweight
你只需买这一根拖把 这会是你用过的最好的拖把
It's the only mop that you're ever gonna buy, the best mop you're ever gonna use
又轻又耐用，我只是说出我的体会
It is lightweight and durable, and that is just me speaking from my experience
作为一个每天要拖地清洁家的人 发自内心的话
As someone who mops their house every single day, from my heart
这女人会是一个全新的商机
This woman's gonna be a whole new business
不会吧
No way
哦，我的天
Oh, my God
你能相信吗？ 你能相信吗？
Can you believe it? Can you believe it?
我以为你肯定会告诉我统计机器坏了
I thought for sure you were gonna tell me that your counting machine was broken
我听了你的话，你是对的
I listened to you You were right
我就是不敢相信竟能成真
I just can't believe that actually happened
我知道
I know
我想你能说我们是生意场上的朋友了
I guess you could say we're friends in commerce
生意上场的朋友
Friends in commerce
对
Yeah
我们互相保证，即使有一天 如果会有那一天
Let's promise each other that if, one day, and that day may come...
我们是彼此生意的对手 我们还是朋友
that we become adversaries in commerce, that we remain friends
因为那才是真正的友谊
Because that's a true friendship indeed
生意场上的朋友
Friends in commerce
我同意，握手吧
I agree Let's shake on it
我们有十台织布机
We've got 10 looms...
织好布后，会在这里缝拖把头
and then when they're completed, this is where the mop heads are sewn
谁生产你的其他部件？
Who makes your parts?
加利福尼亚州的一家工厂
A factory out in California
比这里任何一家都便宜而且高效
It was cheaper and faster than any place around here
很聪明，他们能按时交货吗？
Smart Are they gonna be able to stay on schedule?
能
Yeah
一次
One time
–那里 –谢谢
- Right there - Thank you
–不客气 –这里？
- You're welcome - Right here?
喂？
Hello?
外婆
Mimi
我很气自己那天离她而去
I so hated to leave her that day
我有好多话想对她说
I had so much I wanted to say to her
对我的曾孙女
And to my great granddaughter
我觉得我要待在她身边，守护她
I felt I wanted to stay near her and watch over her
克里斯蒂
Cristy
加利福尼亚那边有个问题
There's a problem in California
加利福尼亚不能出问题 我跟尼尔说了一切都好
There can't be a problem in California I told Neil that everything was fine
杰哈德不断提价，他又提价了
Gerhardt keeps raising his price He just did it again
每把的成本提高了
More money per unit
他不能那样，我们会亏损的
He can't do that We're gonna lose money
我派了一个代表去搞定他
I sent a representative to handle him
代表？我们没有代表
Representative? We don't have a representative
什么代表？
What representative?
佩吉去了
Peggy went
佩吉？
Peggy?
我现在不想谈这个
I don't want to talk about this right now
她想参与进来
She wanted to be part of it
你怎么能派佩吉去？
How could you send Peggy?
她想参与进来
She wanted to be part of it
你们有血缘关系，你们是同父异母的姐妹
You both are blood relatives You're half-sisters
你们相爱，互相尊重，这点非常非常重要
It's very, very important that you love and respect each other
我付了你欠他们的两万，我是迫不得已
I paid them the 20 that you owed them I had to
我让它们完成十万的订单
I got them to fill the order of the 100,000...
每把只加收两美元
with a price increase of only two dollars per unit
我们一分也不能多付了，佩吉 你不明白吗？
We can't increase at all, Peggy Don't you understand?
我们以一定的价格销售
We sold at a certain price
任何成本的提升，尤其是他要求的
Any hikes, especially the ones he's asking for...
意味着我要损失很多钱
mean that I will lose so much money...
以至于会欠下比之前还要多的债
that I'll be in even more debt than I was before
你会赚回来的
You're gonna make it back
我要赚回来？
I'm gonna make it back?
怎么赚？
How?
我有些想法
I've got ideas, you know
我有一些想要做的事
There are things that I'd like to do
我跟他谈了我和爸爸在设想的项目
I spoke to him about a project that Dad and I have been designing
对吧，爸爸？
Right, Dad?
对的，我们在设想
Yes, we did
你知道你的想法要花多少钱吗？
Do you have any idea how much your idea will cost?
你怎么卖？去哪里卖？
How or where you'll sell it?
即使你能把产品生产出来
If you can even manufacture it after it's taken everything we've got...
在我们现在倾其所有 销售这一件产品之后，托你的福
to sell this one product that now, thanks to you...
要花更多的钱？
is going to cost more money?
也许我的产品比你的好
Maybe my product is better than your product
我也能做你在电视上的那些，又不是很难
I can do what you did on TV It's not that hard
这难道不是那个频道的宗旨？ 任何人都可以做？
Isn't that the whole purpose of that channel? It's that everybody could do it?
你妹妹做的那些可不容易
What your sister does is not easy...
但是我们打算做的
but what we were planning to do...
也不是那么难
is not that difficult
听我说
Listen to me
再也不要以我的名义谈
Never speak on my behalf...
我的生意
about my business again
现在我得去一趟加利福尼亚了
Now I have to go to California
请进
引以为傲的商品 由帕克制造厂所有和制造
我有什么可帮你的吗？
Can I help you?
我是乔伊，我来见杰哈德
I'm Joy I'm here to see Gerhardt
他没空
He's not available
我会等
I'll wait
她说她来见杰哈德
She says she's here to see Gerhardt
杰哈德！
Gerhardt!
嗨，我是杰哈德
Hey I'm Gerhardt
我是乔伊
I'm Joy
请进
Come on in
德里克马卡姆是我的老板
Derek Markham is my boss
他住在德克萨斯州
He lives in Texas
帕克制造厂只是他拥有的或 收专利费的其中一家公司而已
Fabri-Pac is one of several companies he owns or collects royalties for
我向他汇报，他定价格
I report to him He makes pricing decisions
我从没见过 也没和这个德里克马卡姆谈过
Well, I've never met or talked to this Derek Markham...
但我和你在电话谈过好多次了
but I've talked to you many times on the phone
我很好奇
And I do find it very curious...
我上电视大获成功后
that the second I'm on television, with a lot of success...
我们产品的造价就涨了
the price for our products goes up
至少对我来说，这很不公平
Seems very unfair to me, to say the least
你们似乎是在压榨我们
Seems like you're shaking us down
你见过格里高利了，我们的工头
You met Gregory, our plant foreman
我们现在很难降低成本
It's very hard for us to lower the cost at this point
我们已经亏了很多钱
We're already losing a lot of money
怎么会呢，除了预付给达拉斯的 德里克马卡姆的
How could that possibly be, with the $500,000 that we've given you...
五万美元专利费
on top of the $50,000 of advance royalties...
我们还支付给你们50万美元
that have gone to a Derek Markham in Dallas
更别说我姐姐付了你们的那笔
And that's not even counting what my sister paid you...
因为你们多收费和出错产生的费用
without my authority, by the way...
顺便说下，还是未经我授权的
for your overcharges and your mistakes
你姐姐付了你拒绝支付的涨价部分
Your sister paid the increase that you refused to pay
她没权这样做，她根本不是我公司的一员
Well, she had no authority to do that She's not an officer of my corporation
我们可以花很多时间和钱去法庭 证明我是对的
You and I could both spend a lot of time and money in court to prove that I'm right...
但那只会让我们的律师更富有
but that would just make our lawyers wealthy...
与此同时我的产品却停产 不能上电视
while my product dies instead of being on television...
就像现在这样
like it could be right now
你可以付更多钱
You can pay more
我付不了更多，我不会
I can't pay more I won't
成本更高了，模具有损耗
Costs are higher Wear and tear on the molds
我们每隔一周都要重做一次
We have to remake them every other week
是吗？我能看看模具吗？
Is that so? Can I see the molds?
它们在机器里
They're in the machines
给你看需要花些时间
It'll take some time to prepare them for you
我能用下洗手间吗？
Is there a bathroom I could use?
可以，走廊走到底 格里高利会带你去
Yeah, it's down the hall Gregory will show you
谢谢
Thanks
帕克制造厂专利 自己拧干拖把模具
什么？
What?
你在这里干什么？
What are you doing in here?
这是什么？
What is this?
这些是我的设计图，是我的模具！
These are my designs, these are my molds!
那些是我们的！
Those are ours!
我们就知道你是个麻烦 警察已经在路上了
And we knew you'd be trouble The cops are on their way
–你一来我们就报警了 –这些是我的模具！
- We called 'em as soon as you showed up! - These are my molds!
是我们的！
Those are ours!
我要把这些带走
I'm taking these with me
我要把这些全部带走
I'm taking all of these with me
我要把这些都打包，我要带走它们
I want all of these boxed up, and I'm taking them
你非法入侵！
You're trespassing!
这不是你们的专利！
It's not your patent!
这些是我的设计！
These are my designs!
不带走我的模具我哪也不会去
I'm not going anywhere without my molds
什么？不，不
What? No No
这不是偷窃，这是我的财产！
This is not stealing, this is my property!
这是我的财产！
This is my property
我拥有这些设计图，这些都是我的 它们属于我！
I have all of these designs These are all mine They belong to me!
她来自别的州，约翰！你认识我15年了！
She's from out of state, John! You've known me 15 years!
好了，走吧，女士，你非法入侵了
All right, come on, ma'am You're trespassing
–什么？ –对，走吧
- What? - Yeah Come on
–我没有非法入侵 –不，你非法入侵了
- I'm not trespassing - Yeah, you're trespassing
我之前在他的办公室
I was in his office
–我不知道，走吧 –他让我进他的…
- You don't know Come on - He let me into his...
杰哈德，我不会放过你的
Gerhardt, you're not gonna get away with this
–我不会放过你的！ –说话小心点
- You're not gonna get away with this! - Be careful what you're saying
–你是个小偷！杰哈德！ –当心，走吧
- You're a thief! You're a thief, Gerhardt! - Be careful, come on, come on
当心，走吧，停住
Be careful Come on, stop it
–这是偷窃！ –嗨嗨，别嚷嚷了，走吧
- This is stealing! - Hey, hey, stop it Come on
好吧
All right
小心脚下，好吧
Watch your step All right
特鲁迪的钱呢，乔伊？
What about Trudy's money, Joy?
你得还特鲁迪的钱
You have to pay back Trudy's money
只会变得越来越糟
This is only getting worse
我觉得势头不妙，乔伊
I predicted tragedy, Joy
你欠下了一大笔债
You're racking up quite a steep bill
我们还不得不飞来这里保释你
We had to fly out here, bail you out
再加上我们额外支付了雷贾克内 一万美元
Plus it cost us an extra $10,000 for Ray Cagney...
这位加利福尼亚的专利律师 帮我们到这份上
this California patent attorney, to get us to this point
我们让州政府撤销了指控
We got the state to decline prosecution
他们认为这是一起合同纠纷
They see it's a contract dispute
当你给德克萨斯的德里克马卡姆 付专利费时
When you paid royalties to Derek Markham in T exas...
你就把所有零部件和模具 归到他们的专利里了
it put all your parts and molds under the umbrella of their patent
我看你带了你的设计图 想证明这是你的设计
I see you brought your drawings and hung them to prove your design
但现在没法起诉他们
But it's impossible to fight it now
你没得到正确的法律咨询
You were not properly advised
克里斯蒂，别闹了！
Cristy, please!
托尼，带她去睡觉
Tony, take her to bed
我不想睡觉，我想待在这里
I don't wanna go to bed I wanna stay here
我付那些专利费
I paid those royalties...
是因为你让我付的
because you told me to
因为你的律师让我付的
Because your lawyer told me to
我们的律师弄错了 生意上有时会发生这种事
Our lawyer was mistaken This happens sometimes in business
你运气不太好
It didn't work out for you
有时是会发生这样的事
It happens sometimes
特鲁迪的律师不是专利律师
Trudy's lawyer is not a patent attorney
我就是那么说的！
Which I said!
而你说我没资格给乔伊提建议
And you said I had no business being Joy's advisor
–现在证明我是对的了！ –你这是帮倒忙，托尼！
- And now it turns out that I was right! - This is not helpful, Tony!
–够了，托尼，拜托 –哦，现在够了？
- That's enough, Tony Please - It's enough, now?
我很抱歉 我希望我能帮上什么忙
I'm very sorry I wish there was more I could do
但是当你姐姐佩吉付了你拒绝支付的
But when your sister Peggy paid the unjustified bills...
不公正的账单后
that you refused to pay...
就已经没办法了
it closed the door on that
尼尔沃克和QVC怎么办？
What about Neil Walker and QVC?
他们不会支付争夺专利的费用吗？
Wouldn't they pay the expenses on defending the patent?
小心点，乔伊
Be careful, Joy
你可能会因对产品的虚假陈述 和未能交付而被起诉
You could be sued for misrepresentation and failure to deliver your product
这是毁灭性的
That's breach
QVC要求你交付有完全专利权的产品
QVC requires that you deliver a fully patented product
我干这一行很久了
I've been doing this for a long time
你会面临漫长的法庭程序 会导致产品停产
You're in for a long court process that will stall your product
而且你还可能败诉
And you will probably lose
我希望我能帮上更多忙
I wish I could do more
保重
Take care, now
你得接受现实，乔伊
You're gonna have to accept the facts, Joy
我是说，这…
I mean, that's...
你差不多欠了五十万美元的债了
You're most of half a million dollars in debt
我不知道你要怎么偿还
I don't know how you're gonna pay it
我们得宣布破产
We have to declare bankruptcy
你得宣布破产
You're gonna have to declare bankruptcy
我得宣布破产
I have to declare bankruptcy
她必须得这样
She has to
–以防我进一步的损失 –对
- To try to contain my losses - Yeah
我得把损失匀回来
I have to write it off
这样很不对
It just seems so wrong
我们那么努力
We've worked so hard
我们一路经历了那么多，现在就放弃的话
We've come so far for us to just give up now
太不公平了
It just seems so unfair!
生意场上何来公平，现实就是这样
Business is unfair That's it
只是没做成，这种事时有发生
It's not working out Well, that's what happens
所以人们不会每天 没事就发明件东西
That's why people don't go around making invention every other day
清醒吧！
Wake up!
都是我的错
It's my fault
是我给她信心，让她认为自己远不止是 在垃圾频道上
I gave her the confidence to think she was more than just an unemployed housewife...
卖塑料厨房用具给其他失业家庭主妇的
selling plastic kitchen stuff to other unemployed housewives...
一个失业家庭主妇
on a junk cable channel
是我的错，不是你的错，亲爱的
It's my fault It's not your fault, honey
是我让她误以为能超越自己
It was my mistake to make her think that she was more than she was
她强迫自己做了她本不该做的事
She pressured herself into doing something she shouldn't have done
你不该给自己压力的
It was wrong of you to put that pressure on yourself
我们不该给你那样的压力
It was wrong of us to put that pressure on you
我需要更多伏特加
I need more vodka
我们不该认为你会在一夜之间 就成为出色的商人
It was wrong of us to think that you'd be an instant business person overnight
当然，那不是你
Of course, this is not who you are
那需要坚强和一些头脑
It takes a kind of toughness, a certain acumen...
显然你都不具备
that you simply don't have
把文书签了
Sign the paper
你得签这些宣告破产的文书，亲爱的
You have to sign these bankruptcy papers, honey
公证师就在外面，我去叫她
The notary's right outside Let me get her
你得立即搬出你的房子
You're gonna have to move out of your house immediately
你得搬去公寓住
You're gonna have to move into an apartment
也许能搬进特鲁迪家的一间房间
Maybe you can move into a room in Trudy's house
和孩子们一起？
With the children?
对，你有空房间
Yeah You have room
她是我的女儿，有什么不行的呢？
She's my daughter Why not?
我们谈谈吧
Let's talk about it
特鲁迪，我们得给她点什么
Trudy, we have to offer her something
还要给？
Again?
为什么要我给？
Why me?
请签名，亲爱的
Please sign, honey
谢谢
Thank you
太婆说你是为振兴家族而生的人
Mimi said you were the one born to help carry the family to success
不，克里斯蒂，太婆错了
No, Cristy Mimi was wrong
世界不给你机会
The world does not give you opportunities
世界毁了你的机会，让你伤心欲绝
The world destroys your opportunity and it breaks your heart
我十岁的时候就该听我妈妈的话
I should have listened to my mother when I was 10 years old
我就该像我妈妈一样
I should have spent the rest of my life...
在看电视和逃避世界中度过一生
watching TV and hiding from the world like my mother
所以我不想再听到太婆说的话了
So I don't wanna hear any more about Mimi
她错了
She was wrong
她异想天开，脑子里都是些愚蠢的想法
She had her head in the clouds and it was full of stupid ideas
致使我也有了愚蠢的想法
And it gave me stupid ideas
就像这个
Like this
这个愚蠢，愚蠢的想法！
This stupid, stupid idea!
妈咪，不要撕掉它们！不要！
Mommy, don't tear them! No!
克里斯蒂，我非常抱歉
Cristy, I'm so sorry
抱歉，克里斯蒂
I'm sorry, Cristy
我非常抱歉
I'm so sorry
去睡觉吧 大家都去睡觉吧
Please go to bed Everybody just go to bed
晚安，妈咪
Good night, Mommy
晚安，甜心，去睡觉吧
Good night, sweetheart Just go to bed
让你失望了，我非常抱歉，乔伊 我非常抱歉
I'm so sorry I failed you, Joy I'm so sorry
别，别说了
Just, just don't
乔伊？乔伊？
Joy? Joy?
乔伊，你在哪里？
Joy, where are you?
德克萨斯州 达拉斯最棒的烧烤店
巴特利特旅馆
门开着
It's open
你可以开着门
You can leave the door open
没人知道我在这里
No one knows I'm here
你甚至都不知道我是谁
You don't even know who I am
我可能是德里克马卡姆 或是他派来搞定你的人
I could be Derek Markham or I might be someone Derek Markham sent to handle you
你没办法起诉我们
You have no case
也许人们认为你来达拉斯 是急于结束自己的生命
Maybe people think you came to Dallas in despair to take your own life...
因为你在野心勃勃的冒险途中 突然陷入了财务困境
because you were in such deep financial trouble suddenly from your little venture
我今早打了通电话去香港
I made a phone call this morning to Hong Kong
当时是加利福尼亚的凌晨一点 但已经是香港的第二天下午五点
It was 1:00 am in California but it was 5:00 pm the following afternoon in Hong Kong
我总是觉得时差很神奇
I always think it's amazing how time works like that
我有幸与克里斯托夫先生通上了电话
And I was fortunate enough to get on the phone with Mr Christopher...
他很友善，挺出乎意料
who I found to be very friendly, which was surprising...
因为我没在加利福尼亚 遇到一个友好的先生
because I really haven't found the gentlemen in California to be very nice...
考虑到我们还有生意往来
considering we're all in business together
欢迎来到生意场吧，我想
Welcome to the world of business, I guess
我告诉克里斯托夫先生，我打电话是来
I told Mr Christopher that the reason that I was calling...
探讨我们产品之间的设计差异
was to discuss the differences in the designs of our products
但是我很快意识到克里斯托夫先生 并不知道
But I quickly learned that Mr Christopher has no idea...
他的自己拧干拖把的香港专利是否值钱 甚至也不知道是否起作用
if his Hong Kong patent for a self-wringing mop is worth anything or if it even works
因为他们没有生产或卖出一根拖把
Because they have not made or sold a single mop
不像我们，卖出了超过二十万根
Unlike us, who have sold over 200,000
而且我付了你五万多的专利费
And I've paid you over $50,000 in advanced royalties...
以付给克里斯托夫的名义
on behalf of Mr Christopher
那是我家人的血汗钱和 我二次抵押房产筹得的钱
Blood money from my family and my second mortgage
结果发现克里斯托夫先生对专利费 并不知情
Turns out Mr Christopher doesn't know anything about those royalties
所以似乎
So it seems...
我们能以诈骗罪和私吞公款罪起诉你了
we have a case of fraud and embezzlement
如果这还不算糟的话
And, as if that weren't bad enough...
我还发现我们的拖把专利书 并无相似之处
I also discovered in the paperwork that our mops actually don't bear any similarities
所以我从没有欠你任何专利费
So I never did owe you any royalties for your patent
这是另一项欺诈
That's another case of fraud
我的律师可以拿下你 但我跟他们说：“给我一天时间”
My lawyers really could go after you, but I told them, "Give me a day"
看你有没有可能补救
To see if maybe you might've made a mistake...
你犯的错误，给你个机会
that you would correct, given the chance
我们会把你付的专利费退给你
We'll pay you back all the royalties you paid us
除了你付的五万，我再付你两万
I'll give you $20,000 on top of paying you back the 50
好啊
Okay
除了你付的五万，我再付你五万
I'll give you $50,000 on top of paying you back the 50
加上利息
Plus interest
我想要回我的所有模具
I want all of my molds back
我要你在这份文书上签上
I want you to sign this piece of paper...
你没有任何权利分成
saying that you have no rights, financially
我再添上 我说的那五万
I'm just gonna add... I said the 50...
加上五万
plus the 50...
再加上利息
plus the interest
我想让你在那两个数字旁 签上你的姓名缩写
So I just want you to initial next to those two numbers as well
签在这里
So just sign there
她一直在忍耐
She put up with just about anything
直到忍无可忍时
Until when she had to bring the hammer down...
她重拳出击
she brought the hammer down
她不知道接下来会发生什么
She couldn't know what was to come
她又申请了一个更赚钱的专利
That she'd go on to make another 100 record-setting patents
细天鹅绒衣架，让衣柜更整洁
Skinny velvet hangers make neater closets
这对很多人来说是了不起的发明
That's a big deal to a lot of people
谁会想到这些？
I mean, who thinks of things like that?
乔伊想到了
Joy did
她那天走在街上的时候并不知道 这些会发生
She didn't know any of this would happen as she walked down the street that day
是的，先生，今晚是圣诞老人走访
Yes, sir, tonight's the night for Ol' Saint Nick to make his yearly visit...
全世界人民的一年一度旅行之夜
to all the folks all over the world
每一座房子都其乐融融充满了期待
There's fun and expectation in every house across the land
说到房子，你说我们要不要瞧瞧这一座？
And speaking of houses, what do you say we take a little look-in on a typical one?
我得说你现在看到的 只是这座房子前廊的一小部分
Now I'll admit that what you see right now is just a small piece of the front of the house...
所有成年人和小孩都一样 这是圣诞老人的魔法时刻
but all you grownups and kids alike, this is the time for Santa's magic...
我想我们能把它变成一座真正的房子
so I think we can make it become a real house
甚至变成一座满是爱的房子
Even a house with love in it
圣诞老人先生，能给我们下点雪吗？
Mr Santa Claus, can we have a little snow, please?
谢谢，很美
Thank you That's fine
圣诞老人，让我看看这座房子的 真实内景
Now, Santa, let me see what it really looks like inside this house
她不知道有一天 能搬进一座漂亮的大房子
She couldn't know that one day she would move into a big beautiful home
她的母亲很高兴
Her mother was happy
她和她母亲一直保持亲密联系 而她和其他家庭成员的关系
She remained close to her, and with the rest of her family...
一直都很复杂
which was, as always, complicated
她会为鲁迪、特鲁迪和佩吉 研发的产品付钱
She would pay for products made by Rudy, Trudy, and Peggy
即使他们研发失败了
Even when they failed
即使他们不厚道地起诉 争她公司的所属权
Even when they wrongly sued for ownership of her company
鲁迪一天天变老 乔伊一直照顾他、爱他
As Rudy got older, Joy continued to take care of him and love him
正如尼尔沃克预见的那样 乔伊的确创下了一番新事业
As Neil Walker predicted, Joy did become a whole new business
甚至比QVC都发展得好
And even outgrew Q VC
–她在和她孩子谈话 –托尼在吗？
- She's talking to her children - Is T ony in there?
是的，托尼在，一家都在
Yes, T ony's in there The family's in there
她的前夫和她最好的朋友 一直都是她坚强的后盾
Her ex-husband and her best friend would remain her steadfast advisers
请耐心等候
Please be patient
我爱你 你们去收拾房间
I love you You guys go and pack your rooms
–晚安，妈妈 –我爱你
- Good night, Mom - I love you
–嗨 –嗨
- Hi - Hi
–欢迎 –谢谢
- Welcome - Thank you
你带了什么？
What do you have?
一个旅行用的衣服清洁器
A traveling clothes cleaner
让我们瞧瞧
Let's see it
你来自孟菲斯吗？
So you're from Memphis?
对，我是
Yes, I am
你是服务生？
You work as a waitress?
对，夫人
Yes, ma'am
好，让我们瞧瞧
All right Let's see it
你自己做的？
You made this yourself?
对，我做的，夫人
Yes, I did, ma'am
我的第一项发明也是我自己做的
I made my first invention myself, too
我喜欢这个，设计的很好
I like this, it's a very good design
谢谢
Thank you
你能多待一天，见见我们的设计师吗？
Can you stay an extra day, meet with our designers?
不行，是因为你老板不同意吗？
No, because of your boss?
你现在待在哪个酒店？
What hotel are you staying in right now?
–假日酒店，夫人 –假日酒店
- The Holiday Inn, ma'am - Holiday Inn
把他们转到雷迪森，弄间套房
Let's move them over to the Radisson, get them a suite
你和孩子会待得更舒服
You'll be more comfortable with your baby
我会给你老板打电话 让他给你多放一天假
I'll call your boss and get it taken care of, give you an extra day...
这样你明天就能来见设计师了
so that tomorrow you can come in, meet with the designers
–我们一步一步来，好吗？ –谢谢
- We can take it step by step, all right? - Thank you
我们会继续探讨你的设想 看看我们能做什么
We'll work on your idea, see if we can do something
这对我意义非凡
This means so much to me
我知道这感觉
I know what it feels like
我知道坐在那张椅子上的感觉
I know what it feels like to be in that chair
–我们明天见，好吗？ –谢谢，夫人
- We'll see you tomorrow, okay? - Thank you, ma'am
祝你好运
And good luck
–谢谢你们能来 –谢谢
- Thank you for coming - Thank you
–去叫下一个人，托尼 –好的
- Go get the next person, Tony - Okay
尼尔
Neil
抱歉，我们现在和巴里有法律纠纷
Sorry, we have legal stuff with Barry, now
是的，我们有
Yes, we do
终于到这一天了
Here we are
生意上的对手
Adversaries in commerce
–也是朋友 –没错
- And friends - Yes
也是朋友
And friends
我要告诉你些事 但别说是我说的
I'm gonna tell you something but you didn't hear it from me
我不知道你是谁 也不知道你在说什么
I don't know who you are or what you're talking about
这就是我想听的
That's what I wanted to hear
巴里要告你，狠狠地告
Barry's gonna come after you, hard
但只是生意 巴里就是这样的人，他是谈判家
But that's just business That's the way Barry is He's a negotiator
归根结底，他需要你
Ultimately, he needs you
他要买下HSN
He's buying HSN
HSN势头正好 他想让你和他一起干
It's all about HSN now, and he wants you to come with him
他需要你
He needs you
你在那里会担任要职
You're going to be very big over there
这就是接下来会发生的事
That's what's going to happen
但是，别说是我说的，好吧？
But, you didn't hear it from me, right?
好，肯定不会 但谢谢你
No, I sure didn't But thank you
见到你真好
It's nice to see you
It's good to see you
再见，朋友
I'll see you around, pal
再见
Yeah
一路走来不容易啊
It's been a long journey
没错，是不容易
Yes, it has
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you
谢谢，尼尔
Thank you, Neil
就是这里 这是个超能力
This right here, this is a special power
这是个超能力
This is a special power
然后我开始造我自己的房子
And then I started to build my very own house...
我会住在那里 然后创造很多美好的东西
where I would live and make wonderful creations...
让全世界都看到和拥有
for all the world to see and love
她走在街上的那天
She didn't know any of this would happen...
并不知道这些会发生
as she walked that day